<?xml version="1.0"?><eml:eml xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.1" system="ess-dive" xsi:schemaLocation="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0 https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0/eml.xsd" packageId="ess-dive-e7951fc82a6c440-20230504T210107163273">  <dataset id="dataset.id">    <alternateIdentifier>paf_685_760</alternateIdentifier>    <title>Lead isotopic compositions of airborne particulates collected from snow and from dry deposition in the East River Watershed, Colorado and at the Southern Sierra Critical Zone Observatory, California</title>    <creator id="1573184780575228">      <individualName>        <givenName>John</givenName>        <surName>Christensen</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>jnchristensen@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-9533-5801</userId>    </creator>    <creator id="7564400771532421">      <individualName>        <givenName>Peggy</givenName>        <surName>O'Day</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>University of California Merced</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>poday@ucmerced.edu</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>    <creator id="8675179119144164">      <individualName>        <givenName>Ugwumsinachi</givenName>        <surName>Nwosu</surName>      </individualName>      <electronicMailAddress>ugwums@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>    <associatedParty id="8927016126601731">      <individualName>        <givenName>Dylan</givenName>        <surName>O'Ryan</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>dporyan@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-1793-9781</userId>      <role>contributor</role>    </associatedParty>    <associatedParty id="7202290574386044">      <organizationName>U.S. DOE &gt; Office of Science &gt; Biological and Environmental Research (BER)</organizationName>      <userId directory="unknown">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/100006206</userId>      <role>fundingOrganization</role>    </associatedParty>    <pubDate>2022</pubDate>    <abstract>      <para>The data set consists of lead (Pb) isotopic ratios (206Pb/207Pb and 208Pb/207Pb, as well as 206Pb/204Pb, 207Pb/204Pb, 208Pb/204Pb) for particulate samples collected from snow and dry deposition. This was part of a study (O’Day et al. 2020) that was looking at the speciation of phosphorous in splits of these samples to evaluate the flux and bio-availability of phosphorous to the mountain sites in the study. The Pb isotopic data allow sourcing of long-range transported Pb, specifically the fraction of Pb sourced in Asia, and so a comparison of the relative distances of PM sources between the high and low elevation sites. Samples were collected at the East River Watershed, CO (dry deposition collected over Sept.-Oct. 2016, show sampling winter 2017) and at the Southern Sierra Critical Zone Observatory (dry deposition collected over Sept-Nov 2016, July-Sept 2017, June-July 2017). The data includes Pb concentration data, as well as calculated fraction of the Pb sourced in Asia. This data set was published in part in O’Day et al. (2020) Phosphorus Speciation in Atmospherically Deposited Particulate Matter and Implications for Terrestrial Ecosystem Productivity. ES&amp;T, https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.9b06150</para>    </abstract>    <keywordSet>      <keyword>aerosols</keyword>      <keyword> long-range atmospheric transport</keyword>      <keyword> lead isotopes</keyword>      <keywordThesaurus>CATEGORICAL:NONE</keywordThesaurus>    </keywordSet>    <keywordSet>      <keyword>Isotopes</keyword>      <keywordThesaurus>VARIABLE:NONE</keywordThesaurus>    </keywordSet>    <additionalInfo>      <section>        <title>Related References</title>        <para>O’Day et al. (2020) Phosphorus Speciation in Atmospherically Deposited Particulate Matter and Implications for Terrestrial Ecosystem Productivity. ES&amp;T, https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.9b06150</para>        <para>Additional metadata on specific locations within the watershed are provided in the following related data package:</para>        <para>Varadharajan C ; Kakalia Z ; Banfield J ; Berkelhammer M ; Brodie E ; Christianson D ; Dafflon B ; Carbone M S ; Carroll R ; Chadwick K D ; Christensen J ; Enquist B J ; Fox P ; Henderson M ; Gochis D ; Kueppers L ; Powell T ; Matheus Carnevali P ; Singha K ; Sorensen P ; Tokunaga T ; Versteeg R ; Wilkins M ; Williams K ; Worsham M ; Wu Y ; Agarwal D (2020): Location Identifiers, Metadata, and Map for Field Measurements at the East River Watershed, Colorado, USA. Watershed Function SFA. doi:10.15485/1660962</para>      </section>    </additionalInfo>    <intellectualRights>      <para>This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, visit http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/.</para>    </intellectualRights>    <coverage>      <geographicCoverage>        <geographicDescription>The East River (ER) is a snow‐dominated, headwater basin of the Upper Colorado River Basin (UCRB) located in the western United States. The ER is the designated testbed of Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory's Watershed Function Scientific Focus Area (WFSFA). Through WFSFA, observational networks have been established to measure stream discharge and precipitation chemistry. The ER is considered representative of many snow‐dominated headwaters of the Rocky Mountains. The study domain encompasses nearly 85 square km, a 1.4‐km vertical drop in elevation (4,120 to 2,760 m) and pristine alpine, subalpine, montane, and riparian ecosystems. The ER contains high‐energy mountain streams to low‐energy meandering floodplains and is eroding primarily into the Cretaceous, carbon‐rich, marine shale of the Mancos Formation. Additional metadata on specific locations within the watershed are provided in the following related data package: Varadharajan C. et al. (2020) doi:10.15485/1660962</geographicDescription>        <boundingCoordinates>          <westBoundingCoordinate>-107.05</westBoundingCoordinate>          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-106.88</eastBoundingCoordinate>          <northBoundingCoordinate>39.034</northBoundingCoordinate>          <southBoundingCoordinate>38.88</southBoundingCoordinate>        </boundingCoordinates>      </geographicCoverage>      <temporalCoverage>        <rangeOfDates>          <beginDate>            <calendarDate>2016-09-17</calendarDate>          </beginDate>          <endDate>            <calendarDate>2017-08-31</calendarDate>          </endDate>        </rangeOfDates>      </temporalCoverage>    </coverage>    <contact id="2290965931010989">      <individualName>        <givenName>John</givenName>        <surName>Christensen</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>jnchristensen@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-9533-5801</userId>    </contact>    <methods>      <methodStep>        <description>          <para>Lead Isotopic Analysis</para>          <para>For details of particulate matter sample collection methods, see O’Day et al. (2020) https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.9b06150. Lead isotopic analysis followed methods used by Ewing et al. (1), Christensen et al. (2), Pierce et al. (3), and Asher et al. (4) using a Neptune Plus (Thermo-Fisher) multi-collector ICP source mass spectrometer (MCICPMS) at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory (LBNL). Aliquots of solutions from samples dissolved for total element analysis were taken to provide 10-100 ng of Pb for isotopic analysis.  The aliquots were dried down in Teflon vials (Savillex, LLC), brought up again in high purity 0.5 M HBr (Seastar Chemicals) and loaded on new AG1x8 resin (BioRad) using small Teflon columns. The columns were then eluted with 0.5 M HBr to strip matrix elements, and Pb collected off the columns with high purity 6M HCl (Seastar Chemicals). The separated Pb was then dried down and taken up again in 1 ml 0.3N HNO3 (high purity, Seastar Chemicals) from which 10% by volume was taken for Pb concentration determination using the Neptune Plus MC-ICPMS. Based on this result, the remaining sample was spiked with natural Tl (NIST SRM997) at ~5 ng Tl per 25 ng sample Pb. The isotopic composition of the Tl-sample Pb mixture was measured on the Neptune Plus using the monitored 230Tl/205Tl ratio to correct 206Pb/207Pb, 208Pb/207Pb for instrumental mass fractionation correction with normalization to the NIST SRM981 Pb isotopic standard spiked with Tl as above. Sample 206Pb/207Pb, 208Pb/207Pb were also corrected for total chemistry blank, which in most cases was less than 1% of sample Pb mass. Analytical uncertainties of the 206Pb/207Pb and 208Pb/207Pb ratios were better than ±0.01 ‰ (2σ) based on replicates of SRM981.</para>          <para>Calculation of the Fraction of Asian Pb</para>          <para>The measured 206Pb/207Pb and 208Pb/207Pb of the PM samples were used to calculate the fraction of Asian Pb in the sample using a mixing model presented by Ewing et al. (1) (cf. (2-14)). First the parameter Δ208Pbsmpl is calculated, which represents the horizontal displacement of the sample from the California Pb isotope data array using Eq. A (1):</para>          <para>Δ208Pbsmpl = 1000[(208Pb/207Pb)smpl – (208Pb/207Pb)CA]	Eq. A</para>          <para>where (208Pb/207Pb)CA is the ratio the sample would have if with its measured 206Pb/207Pb it plotted on the California array. The fraction of Asian Pb in a sample (FAsianPb) is then calculated from Eq. B (1):</para>          <para>FAsiaPb = Δ208Pbsmpl/Δ208PbAsia	Eq. B</para>          <para>Δ208PbAsia represents the horizontal offset of Asian sources from the California array and for 100 % Asian Pb the threshold value is 25. For samples with Δ208Pbsmpl equal to zero (or less), the sample plots on the California Array (or to the left of it) and the fraction of Asian Pb is taken as zero.</para>          <para>References</para>          <para>1. S. A. Ewing et al., Pb Isotopes as an Indicator of the Asian Contribution to Particulate Air Pollution in Urban California. Environ. Sci. Technol. 44, 8911-8916 (2010).</para>          <para>2.	J. N. Christensen et al., Unraveling the sources of ground level ozone in the Intermountain Western United States using Pb isotopes. Sci. Total Environ. 530, 519-525 (2015).</para>          <para>3.	A. M. Pierce, M. S. Gustin, J. N. Christensen, S. M. Loria-Salazar, Use of multiple tools including lead isotopes to decipher sources of ozone and reactive mercury to urban and rural locations in Nevada, USA. Sci. Total Environ. 615, 1411-1427 (2018).</para>          <para>4.	E. C. Asher et al., The Transport of Asian Dust and Combustion Aerosols and Associated Ozone to North America as Observed From a Mountaintop Monitoring Site in the California Coast Range. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres 123, 5667-5680 (2018).</para>        </description>      </methodStep>    </methods>    <project id="024b867d-25e3-4025-b68c-6598aded7aa2" scope="system" system="ess-dive">      <title>Watershed Function SFA</title>      <personnel>        <individualName>          <givenName>Eoin</givenName>          <surName>Brodie</surName>        </individualName>        <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>        <electronicMailAddress>elbrodie@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>        <role>Principal Investigator</role>      </personnel>    </project>    <otherEntity id="ess-dive-5ab0e253a4bdddb-20220112T000129170299">      <entityName>Pb isotope data from O'Day et al 2020.xlsx</entityName>      <entityType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</entityType>    </otherEntity>    <otherEntity id="ess-dive-9ffb26bf9b0a2a7-20220112T000129646599">      <entityName>Pb isotope data from O'Day et al 2020.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity>  </dataset></eml:eml>