<?xml version="1.0"?><eml:eml xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.1" system="ess-dive" xsi:schemaLocation="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0 https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0/eml.xsd" packageId="ess-dive-cd3995361c524ec-20230819T005239262">  <dataset id="dataset.id"><alternateIdentifier>10.15485/1660456</alternateIdentifier><alternateIdentifier>paf_495_924</alternateIdentifier><title>Total Dissolved Nitrogen and Ammonia Data for the East River Watershed, Colorado (2015-2023)</title><creator id="4379061530365859">      <individualName><givenName>Wenming</givenName><surName>Dong</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>wenmingdong@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0003-2074-8887</userId>    </creator><creator id="1161077969753416">      <individualName><givenName>Curtis</givenName><surName>Beutler</surName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>curtis.beutler@colorado.edu</electronicMailAddress>          </creator><creator id="9931591443093892">      <individualName><givenName>Nick</givenName><surName>Bouskill</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>njbouskill@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-6577-8724</userId>    </creator><creator id="2910080218327144">      <individualName><givenName>Wendy</givenName><surName>Brown</surName></individualName><organizationName>Bugs Unlimited, LLC</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>wsbrown@frontier.net</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-7237-1797</userId>    </creator><creator id="5831631814574623">      <individualName><givenName>Alexander</givenName><surName>Newman</surName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>alexnewman760@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>          </creator><creator id="9448742007269942">      <individualName><givenName>Dylan</givenName><surName>O'Ryan</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>dporyan@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-1793-9781</userId>    </creator><creator id="1699563474224545">      <individualName><givenName>Roelof</givenName><surName>Versteeg</surName></individualName><organizationName>Subsurface Insights</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>roelof.versteeg@subsurfaceinsights.com</electronicMailAddress>                </creator><creator id="5671961144515408">      <individualName><givenName>Kenneth</givenName><surName>Williams</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>khwilliams@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3568-1155</userId>    </creator><associatedParty id="4252624530220199">      <individualName><givenName>Charuleka</givenName><surName>Varadharajan</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>cvaradharajan@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-4142-3224</userId>      <role>contributor</role>    </associatedParty><associatedParty id="3195536027986209">      <individualName><givenName>Robert</givenName><surName>Crystal-Ornelas</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>rcrystalornelas@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-6339-1139</userId>      <role>contributor</role>    </associatedParty><associatedParty id="2526757667968848">      <individualName><givenName>Erek</givenName><surName>Alper</surName></individualName><organizationName>Subsurface Insights</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>erek.alper@subsurfaceinsights.com</electronicMailAddress>                  <role>contributor</role>    </associatedParty><associatedParty id="1063390342255328"><organizationName>U.S. DOE &#x3E; Office of Science &#x3E; Biological and Environmental Research (BER)</organizationName>            <userId directory="unknown">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/100006206</userId>      <role>fundingOrganization</role>    </associatedParty><pubDate>2023</pubDate>                                                                    <abstract><para>This data package contains mean values for total dissolved nitrogen (TDN) and ammonia concentrations for water samples taken from the East River Watershed in Colorado. The East River is part of the Watershed Function Scientific Focus Area (WFSFA) located in the Upper Colorado River Basin, United States. TDN was analyzed using a Shimadzu Total Nitrogen Module (TNM-1) combined with the TOC-VCSH analyzer (Shimadzu Corporation, Japan). TNM-1 is a non-specific measurement of total nitrogen (TN). All nitrogen species in samples are combusted to nitrogen monoxide and nitrogen dioxide, then reacted with ozone to form an excited state of nitrogen dioxide. Upon returning to ground state, light energy is emitted. Then, TDN is measured using a chemiluminescence detector. Ammonia was determined using a Lachat's QuikChem 8500 Series 2 Flow Injection Analysis System (LACHAT Instruments, QuckChem 8500 series 2, Automated Ion Analyzer, Loveland, Colorado). When ammonia in water samples is heated (60 degrees C) with salicylate and hypochlorite in an alkaline phosphate buffer, an emerald green color is produced which is proportional to the ammonia concentration. The color is intensified by the addition of nitroprusside. Ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid (EDTA) is added to the buffer to prevent the interference of metal ions (Ca, Mg, and Fe etc.). Ammonia-N is then determined by LACHAT flow injection and a colorimetric assay at an absorbance wavelength 660 nm. (Reference: LACHAT Instruments: QuickChem Method 90-107-06-3-A, Determination of Ammonia by Flow Injection Analysis (High Throughput, Salicylate Method/DCIC) (Multi Matrix method). Written by Lynn Egan (Application group), February 08, 2011.) All files are labeled by location and variable, and data reported are the mean values upon replicate measurements. All samples were analyzed under a rigorous quality assurance and quality control (QA/QC) process as detailed in the methods. This data package contains (1) a zip file (tdn_ammonia_data_2015-2023.zip) containing a total of 279 files: 278 data files of ammonia and TDN data from across the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory (LBNL) Watershed Function Scientific Focus Area (SFA) which is reported in .csv files per location and a locations.csv (1 file) with latitude and longitude for each location; (2) a file-level metadata (v4_20230808_flmd.csv) file that lists each file contained in the dataset with associated metadata; (3) a data dictionary (v4_20230808_dd.csv) file that contains terms/column_headers used throughout the files along with a definition, units, and data type; (4) PDF and docx files for the determination of Method Detection Limits (MDLs) for DIC and NPOC data; and (5) PDF and docx files for the determination of Method Detection Limits (MDLs) for Ammonia and the Interferences by LACHAT Flow Injection Analysis. There are a total of 96 locations containing isotope data </para><para>Update 2020-10-07: Updated the data files to remove times from the timestamps, so that only dates remain. The data values have not changed.</para><para>Update 2021-04-11: Added Determination of Method Detection Limits (MDLs) for DIC, NPOC and TDN Analyses and Determination of Method Detection Limit for Ammonia and the Interferences by LACHAT Flow Injection Analysis documents, which can be accessed as PDFs or with Microsoft Word.Update on 6/10/2022: versioned updates to this dataset was made along with these changes: (1) updated total dissolved nitrogen and ammonia data for all locations up to 2021-12-31, (2) removal of units from column headers in datafiles, (3) added row underneath headers to contain units of variables, (4) restructure of units to comply with CSV reporting format requirements, (5) added -9999 for empty numerical cells, and (6) the addition of the file-level metadata (flmd.csv) and data dictionary (dd.csv) were added to comply with the File-Level Metadata Reporting Format.</para><para>Update on 2022-09-09: Updates were made to reporting format specific files (file-level metadata and data dictionary) to correct swapped file names, add additional details on metadata descriptions on both files, add a header_row column to enable parsing, and add version number and date to file names (v2_20220909_flmd.csv and v2_20220909_dd.csv).</para><para>Update on 2022-12-20: Updates were made to both the data files and reporting format specific files. Units were listed incorrectly, but have been fixed to reflect correct units (ug/L). File level metadata (flmd) and data dictionary (dd) files were updated to reflect the updated versions of these files. Available data was added up until 2022-06-01.</para><para>Update on 2023-08-08: Updates were made to both the data files and reporting format specific files. New available anion data was added, up until 2023-01-05. The file level metadata and data dictionary files were updated to reflect the additional data added.</para></abstract><keywordSet><keyword>geochemical</keyword><keyword> tnd</keyword><keyword> ammonia</keyword><keyword> water quality/water chemistry</keyword><keyword> ground water</keyword><keyword>ESS-DIVE File Level Metadata Reporting Format</keyword><keyword>surface water</keyword><keyword>ESS-DIVE CSV File Formatting Guidelines Reporting Format</keyword><keywordThesaurus>CATEGORICAL:NONE</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet><keywordSet xmlns:sw="eml://ecoinformatics.org/software-2.1.1" xmlns:cit="eml://ecoinformatics.org/literature-2.1.1" xmlns:ds="eml://ecoinformatics.org/dataset-2.1.1" xmlns:prot="eml://ecoinformatics.org/protocol-2.1.1" xmlns:doc="eml://ecoinformatics.org/documentation-2.1.1" xmlns:res="eml://ecoinformatics.org/resource-2.1.1" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; TERRESTRIAL HYDROSPHERE &#x3E; WATER QUALITY/WATER CHEMISTRY</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; TERRESTRIAL HYDROSPHERE &#x3E; GROUND WATER</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; TERRESTRIAL HYDROSPHERE &#x3E; SURFACE WATER</keyword><keywordThesaurus>CATEGORICAL:GCMD</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet><keywordSet><keyword>Dissolved Ammonia</keyword><keyword>Total Dissolved Nitrogen</keyword><keywordThesaurus>VARIABLE:NONE</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet><keywordSet xmlns:sw="eml://ecoinformatics.org/software-2.1.1" xmlns:cit="eml://ecoinformatics.org/literature-2.1.1" xmlns:ds="eml://ecoinformatics.org/dataset-2.1.1" xmlns:prot="eml://ecoinformatics.org/protocol-2.1.1" xmlns:doc="eml://ecoinformatics.org/documentation-2.1.1" xmlns:res="eml://ecoinformatics.org/resource-2.1.1" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; TERRESTRIAL HYDROSPHERE &#x3E; SURFACE WATER &#x3E; SURFACE WATER CHEMISTRY</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; TERRESTRIAL HYDROSPHERE &#x3E; GROUND WATER &#x3E; GROUNDWATER CHEMISTRY</keyword><keywordThesaurus>VARIABLE:GCMD</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet>                    <additionalInfo><section><title>Related References</title><para>Velliquette, T., Welch, J., Crow, M., Devarakonda, R., Heinz, S., Crystal-Ornelas, R. (2021). ESS-DIVE Reporting Format for Comma-separated Values (CSV) File Structure. Environmental Systems Science Data Infrastructure for a Virtual Ecosystem (ESS-DIVE), ESS-DIVE Repository. https://doi.org/10.15485/1734841</para><para>Velliquette, T., Welch, J., Crow, M., Devarakonda, R., Heinz, S., Crystal-Ornelas, R. (2021). ESS-DIVE Reporting Format for File-level Metadata. Environmental Systems Science Data Infrastructure for a Virtual Ecosystem (ESS-DIVE), ESS-DIVE Repository. https://doi.org/10.15485/1734840</para><para>Additional metadata on specific locations within the watershed are provided in the following related data package:</para><para>Varadharajan C ; Kakalia Z ; Burrus M ; O'Ryan D ; Alper E ; Banfield J ; Berkelhammer M ; Beutler C ; Brodie E ; Brown W ; Carbone M S ; Carroll R ; Christianson D ; Chou C ; Crystal-Ornelas R ; Chadwick K D ; Christensen J ; Dafflon B ; Elbashandy H ; Enquist B J ; Fox P ; Gochis D ; Henderson M ; Johnson D ; Kueppers L ; Matheus Carnevali P ; Newman A ; Powell T ; Singha K ; Sorensen P ; Sprenger M ; Tokunaga T ; Versteeg R ; Wilkins M ; Williams K ; Worsham M ; Wong C ; Wu Y ; Agarwal D (2022): Location Identifiers, Metadata, and Map for Field Measurements at the East River Watershed, Colorado, USA (Version 3.0). Watershed Function SFA, ESS-DIVE repository. Dataset. doi:10.15485/1660962</para></section></additionalInfo>    <intellectualRights><para>This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, visit http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/.</para></intellectualRights>    <coverage>      <geographicCoverage>        <geographicDescription>The East River (ER) is a snow‐dominated, headwater basin of the Upper Colorado River Basin (UCRB) located in the western United States. The ER is the designated testbed of Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory's Watershed Function Scientific Focus Area (WFSFA). Through WFSFA, observational networks have been established to measure stream discharge and precipitation chemistry. The ER is considered representative of many snow‐dominated headwaters of the Rocky Mountains. The study domain encompasses nearly 85 square km, a 1.4‐km vertical drop in elevation (4,120 to 2,760 m) and pristine alpine, subalpine, montane, and riparian ecosystems. The ER contains high‐energy mountain streams to low‐energy meandering floodplains and is eroding primarily into the Cretaceous, carbon‐rich, marine shale of the Mancos Formation. Additional metadata on specific locations within the watershed are provided in the following related data package: Varadharajan C. et al. (2022) doi:10.15485/1660962</geographicDescription>        <boundingCoordinates><westBoundingCoordinate>-107.05</westBoundingCoordinate><eastBoundingCoordinate>-106.88</eastBoundingCoordinate><northBoundingCoordinate>39.034</northBoundingCoordinate><southBoundingCoordinate>38.88</southBoundingCoordinate></boundingCoordinates>      </geographicCoverage>      <temporalCoverage><rangeOfDates><beginDate><calendarDate>2015-10-21</calendarDate></beginDate><endDate><calendarDate>2023-01-05</calendarDate></endDate></rangeOfDates></temporalCoverage>    </coverage><contact id="2341914587144582">      <individualName><givenName>Kenneth</givenName><surName>Williams</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>khwilliams@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3568-1155</userId>    </contact><publisher xmlns:sw="eml://ecoinformatics.org/software-2.1.1" xmlns:cit="eml://ecoinformatics.org/literature-2.1.1" xmlns:ds="eml://ecoinformatics.org/dataset-2.1.1" xmlns:prot="eml://ecoinformatics.org/protocol-2.1.1" xmlns:doc="eml://ecoinformatics.org/documentation-2.1.1" xmlns:res="eml://ecoinformatics.org/resource-2.1.1" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" id="9038001878850754">          <organizationName>Watershed Function SFA</organizationName></publisher><methods><methodStep>        <description><para>1. TDN QA, Samples Preparation and Storage</para><para>- Water samples for TDN analysis were filtered in the field using 0.45 micrometer Millipore filters, and collected in no-headspace 40 mL glass vials with polypropylene open-top caps and butyl rubber septa (VWR TraceClean).</para><para>- The samples were transported to the laboratory on ice and stored in 4 degrees C refrigerator until analysis.</para><para>2. TDN QC</para><para>- First, perform blank solution checks with Milli-Q water. which used for preparation of calibrations and QC check standards.</para><para>- Then, analyze against the QC check standards to validate the calibration curves obtained. The QC check standards are repeated every 10 to 20 samples to monitor the instrument performance and potential drift. The QC check standard solutions are prepared with vender certified or NIST SRM solutions.</para><para>3. TDN Data Processing and Report:</para><para>- If find a problem with the calibrations (i.e., non-linear calibration) and the results from blank and QC check standards, then need to do troubleshooting and conduct the QA/QC processes again until the QA/QC results are satisfied.</para><para>- Review sample data results: if find unusual or odd data points and potential contaminations, re-run or report the problems and make notes in data reports.</para><para>- Carefully convert the text data files originally generated from instrument software to a more useable format (i.e. Excel files).</para><para>- Send the reports to SFA Watershed Function Data Management for further review and input to database.</para><para>1. Ammonia QA</para><para>Samples Preparation and Storage:</para><para>- Water samples were filtered in the field using 0.45 micrometer Millipore filters, and collected with 20 mL disposable scintillation vials (polypropylene).</para><para>- The samples were transported to the laboratory on ice and freeze stored in -20 degree C freezer until analysis.</para><para>Lachat Instrument maintenance and optimization:</para><para>- Prior to each analysis, warm up the instrument until the detection cell temperature stabilized at 60 degree C, rinse the flow lines with fresh degassed MQ-water, and then rinse reagents until the signal volt is stabilized in ready conditions. After use, rinse thoroughly with MQ-water and then dry with air to remove the residuals in the flow lines</para><para>- Routine conduct instrument mechanic check, and check the tubing connections for potential leaks/clogs, and replace consumable parts, depending on usage (e.g., pump tubings for reagent injection).</para><para>- Prepare fresh reagents using fresh degassed MQ-water when reagents either expired or precipitates occurred.</para><para>- Make calibration curves with 5 - 6 points of standard calibration solutions with concentration range (ppm) covering the sample concentrations, and ensure a good linear co-relationship with r^2 (r squared) greater or equal to 0.995 obtained.</para><para>2. Ammonia QC</para><para>- First, perform blank solution checks with Milli-Q water. which used for preparation of calibrations and QC check standards.</para><para>- Then, analyze against the QC check standards to validate the calibration curves obtained. The QC check standards are repeated every 10 to 20 samples to monitor the instrument performance and potential drift. The QC check standard solutions are prepared with vender certified and the SRM (from NIST) solutions.</para><para>3. Ammonia Data Processing and Report</para><para>- If find a problem with the calibrations (i.e., non-linear calibration) and the results from blank and QC check standards, then need to do troubleshooting and conduct the QA/QC processes again until the QA/QC results are satisfied.</para><para>- Review sample data results: if find unusual or odd data points and potential contaminations, re-run or report the problems and make notes in data reports.</para><para>- Carefully convert the text data files originally generated from instrument software to a more useable format (i.e. Excel files).</para><para>- Send the reports to SFA Watershed Function Data Management for further review and input to database.</para></description>      </methodStep>          </methods><project id="024b867d-25e3-4025-b68c-6598aded7aa2" scope="system" system="ess-dive">      <title>Watershed Function SFA</title>      <personnel>        <individualName>          <givenName>Eoin</givenName>          <surName>Brodie</surName>        </individualName>        <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Lab</organizationName>        <electronicMailAddress>elbrodie@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>        <role>Principal Investigator</role>      </personnel>    </project><otherEntity id="ess-dive-5fc0555ac7d95c3-20210420T171821367">      <entityName>Detemination_of_Method_Detection_Limits__MDLs__for_DIC__NPOC_and_TDN_Analyses__Shimadzu_.pdf</entityName>      <entityType>application/pdf</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-65e43ec9283c0fc-20210420T171814192">      <entityName>Detemination_of_Method_Detection_Limit_for_Ammonia_and_the_Interferences_by_LACHAT_Flow_Injection_Analysis_by_Wenming_Dong.pdf</entityName>      <entityType>application/pdf</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-ead0b7f2db22296-20210412T041504118">      <entityName>Detemination_of_Method_Detection_Limit_for_Ammonia_and_the_Interferences_by_LACHAT_Flow_Injection_Analysis_by_Wenming_Dong.docx</entityName>      <entityType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-2c71e95ad2344ea-20210412T041504133">      <entityName>Detemination_of_Method_Detection_Limits__MDLs__for_DIC__NPOC_and_TDN_Analyses__Shimadzu_.docx</entityName>      <entityType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-c924a99c907e8f4-20230810T171143314"><entityName>tdn_ammonia_data_2015_2023.zip</entityName><entityType>application/zip</entityType></otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-0a159af74619547-20230810T171143327"><entityName>v4_20230808_dd.csv</entityName><entityType>text/csv</entityType></otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-155c85d46b4f025-20230810T171143332"><entityName>v4_20230808_flmd.csv</entityName><entityType>text/csv</entityType></otherEntity>                                              </dataset></eml:eml>