<?xml version="1.0"?><eml:eml xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.1" system="ess-dive" xsi:schemaLocation="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0 https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0/eml.xsd" packageId="ess-dive-6021b07908998f5-20230808T203101587">  <dataset id="dataset.id"><title>Chemistry data from soils and soil incubation experiments from the whole-soil warming experiment at Blodgett Forest, CA, 2018, from: “Metabolic capabilities mute positive response to direct and indirect impacts of warming throughout the soil profile”</title><creator id="1660962309903778">      <individualName><givenName>Nicholas</givenName><surName>Dove</surName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>ndove7@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>            <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0003-1152-956X</userId>    </creator><creator id="8915486550954900">      <individualName><givenName>Margaret</givenName><surName>Torn</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>mstorn@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8174-0099</userId>    </creator><creator id="8261293668498251">      <individualName><givenName>Stephen</givenName><surName>Hart</surName></individualName><organizationName>University of California Merced</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>shart4@ucmerced.edu</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-9023-6943</userId>    </creator><creator id="3684167446378631">      <individualName><givenName>Neslihan</givenName><surName>Tas</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>ntas@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7525-2331</userId>    </creator><associatedParty id="3991262624975275"><organizationName>US.DOE. &#x3E; Office of Science &#x3E; Biological and Environmental Research (BER)</organizationName>            <role>fundingOrganization</role>    </associatedParty>                        <pubDate>2022</pubDate>        <abstract><para>This dataset contains soil chemistry data of soils from the whole-soil warming experiment at Blodgett Forest in June 2018, and from laboratory incubation experiments conducted with a subset of those soils. Soil samples were collected at five different depths down to 80 cm from soil plots continuously heated by 4°C above ambient temperature for 4.5 years, and from the respective unheated control plots. Incubation experiments were conducted for 28 days with soils collected between 10-30 cm (“surface soils”) and 60-80 cm (“subsoils”) from heated and unheated field plots, amended in the laboratory with cellobiose (C, carbon amendment), or cellobiose plus ammonium and phosphate (CNP, combined carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus amendment). The dataset includes separate files for: (i) total carbon and nitrogen concentrations of initial field soils; (ii) carbon dioxide efflux rates at multiple times throughout the incubation experiments, and respective cumulative carbon dioxide efflux rates, as well as inorganic nitrogen concentrations at the beginning and end of the incubations, and net nitrogen mineralization rates and carbon use efficiency calculated at the end of the incubation. Analysis of these data has been published in Dove et al., (2021), “Metabolic capabilities mute positive response to direct and indirect impacts of warming throughout the soil profile. Nat. Commun. 12:2089”, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-22408-5. This research was performed as part of the TES Belowground Biogeochemistry SFA project at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory.</para></abstract><keywordSet><keyword>Earth Science &#x3E; Land Science &#x3E; Soils &#x3E; Carbon &#x3E; Soil organic Carbon (SOC)</keyword><keyword>Earth Science &#x3E; Land Science &#x3E; Soils &#x3E; Nitrogen</keyword><keyword>Earth Science &#x3E; Land Science &#x3E; Soils &#x3E; Phosphorus</keyword><keyword>Earth Science &#x3E; Land Science &#x3E; Soils &#x3E; Soil Respiration &#x3E; Heterotrophic respiration</keyword><keyword>Earth Science &#x3E; Land Science &#x3E; Soils &#x3E; Microbial Carbon Use Efficiency</keyword><keyword>ESS-DIVE CSV File Formatting Guidelines Reporting Format</keyword><keyword>ESS-DIVE File Level Metadata Reporting Format</keyword><keywordThesaurus>CATEGORICAL:NONE</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet><keywordSet><keyword>Earth Science &#x3E; Land Science &#x3E; Soils &#x3E; Soil Depth</keyword><keyword>Earth Science &#x3E; Land Science &#x3E; Soils &#x3E; Soil Temperature</keyword><keyword>Earth Science &#x3E; Land Science &#x3E; Soils &#x3E; Nitrification Rate</keyword><keyword>soil_mass_content_of_carbon</keyword><keyword>soil_mass_content_of_nitrogen</keyword><keyword>soil_mass_content_of_inorganic_ammonium_expressed_as_nitrogen</keyword><keyword>soil_mass_content_of_inorganic_nitrate_expressed_as_nitrogen</keyword><keyword>microbial_carbon_use_efficiency</keyword><keywordThesaurus>VARIABLE:NONE</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet>            <additionalInfo><section><title>Related References</title><para>Dove, N. C., M. S. Torn, S. C. Hart, and N. Taş. 2021. Metabolic capabilities mute positive response to direct and indirect impacts of warming throughout the soil profile. Nature Communications 12:2089. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-22408-5</para><para>Dijkstra, P., Thomas, S. C., Heinrich, P. L., Koch, G. W., Schwartz, E., Hungate, B. A. (2011). Effect of temperature on metabolic activity of intact microbial communities: evidence for altered metabolic pathway activity but not for increased maintenance respiration and reduced carbon use efficiency. Soil Biol. Biochem. 43, 2023–203. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soilbio.2011.05.018</para><para>Hicks Pries, C. E., Castanha, C., Porras, R. C., Torn, M. S. (2017). The whole-soil carbon flux in response to warming. Science 355, 1420–1423. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aal1319.</para><para>Hicks Pries, C. E., Sulman, B. N., West, C., O'Neill, C., Poppleton, E., Porras, R. C., Castanha, C., Zhu, B., Wiedemeier, D. B., Torn, M. S. (2018). Root litter decomposition slows with soil depth. Soil Biol. Biochem. 125, 103–114. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soilbio.2018.07.002.</para><para>Soong, J. L., Castanha, C., Hicks Pries, C. E., Ofiti, N., Porras, R. C., Riley, W. J., Schmidt, M. W., Torn, M. S. (2021). Five years of whole-soil warming led to loss of subsoil carbon stocks and increased CO2 efflux. Sci. Adv. 7, eabd1343. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.abd1343.</para></section></additionalInfo>    <intellectualRights><para>This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, visit http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/.</para></intellectualRights>    <coverage>      <geographicCoverage>        <geographicDescription>Samples were collected from a long-term warming experiment of the soil profile down to one-meter depth, ongoing since 2014 at the University of California Blodgett Experimental Forest, Sierra Nevada, CA (see Hicks Pries et al., 2017 and Soong et al., 2021). The site has been described in detail by Hicks Pries et al. (2018). Briefly, Blodgett forest is located in a Mediterranean climate with mean annual precipitation of 1,660 mm and a mean annual air temperature of 12.5°C. The soil was classified as Alfisol of granitic origin, and has a developed O horizon. The site is a mixed coniferous forest with ponderosa pine (Pinus ponderosa), sugar pine (Pinus lambertiana), incense cedar (Calodefrus decurrens), white fir (Abies concolor) and douglas fir (Pseudotsuga menziesii) as dominant tree species. The mean annual soil temperature ranges between 11.5 and 10.4°C at 5 and 100 cm depths, respectively, although soil temperatures vary annually between 0-29°C, 1-19°C and 2-16°C at 5, 30 and 100 cm depth, respectively.</geographicDescription>        <boundingCoordinates><westBoundingCoordinate>-120.661758</westBoundingCoordinate><eastBoundingCoordinate>-120.660948</eastBoundingCoordinate><northBoundingCoordinate>38.912527</northBoundingCoordinate><southBoundingCoordinate>38.912130</southBoundingCoordinate></boundingCoordinates>      </geographicCoverage>      <temporalCoverage><rangeOfDates><beginDate><calendarDate>2018-06-01</calendarDate></beginDate><endDate><calendarDate>2018-07-02</calendarDate></endDate></rangeOfDates></temporalCoverage>    </coverage><contact id="4478550952713337">      <individualName><givenName>Nicholas</givenName><surName>Dove</surName></individualName><electronicMailAddress>ndove7@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>            <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0003-1152-956X</userId>    </contact><publisher id="2713342578251844">          <organizationName>Belowground Biogeochemistry Scientific Focus Area</organizationName></publisher><methods><methodStep>        <description><para>Adapted from: Dove, N. C., M. S. Torn, S. C. Hart, and N. Taş. 2021. Metabolic capabilities mute positive response to direct and indirect impacts of warming throughout the soil profile. Nature Communications 12:2089. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-22408-5</para><para>Step 1: Field warming experiment, and sample collection and characterization</para><para>The heating treatment warmed the soil 4 °C above ambient temperatures to 1 m depth while maintaining the natural temperature gradient with depth. The experimental design consisted of three paired heated plots and unheated control plots (circular, 3 m in diameter). Twenty-two 2.4 m long steel pipes surrounded each plot, at 0.25 m beyond the plot perimeter to mitigate potential hot spots near the heaters. In heated plots, resistance heater cable (BriskHeat, Ohio, USA) was placed inside the pipes, which were then filled with sand. Steel pipes around the control plots contained sand only. Two concentric rings of heater cable at 1 and 2 m in diameter, 5 cm below the soil surface, were installed to compensate for surface heat loss. Unheated cables were installed similarly in control plots. Power to the heaters was routed through silicon-controlled rectifiers (SCRs, Watlow, Missouri, USA) controlled by a CR1000 datalogger (Campbell Scientific, Utah, USA) through a current-to-voltage converter (SDM-CVO4, Campbell Scientific, Utah, USA). The amount of power supplied to the deep heaters was based on the temperature difference between paired control and heated thermistors at 75 and 100 cm depth at a radial distance of 0.75 m from plot center. Power supplied to the surface heaters was based on the temperature difference of thermistors at 15 and 20 cm depth at a radial distance of 0 and 0.75 m from plot center.</para><para>In June 2018, we sampled one soil core from each plot using a 5-cm diameter AMS corer (AMS Inc. Hayward Falls, ID, USA) and extracted the following depths: 0-10 cm, 10-30 cm, 30-45 cm, 45-60 cm, and 60-80 cm. Polycarbonate core sleeves were sterilized prior to sampling and were used only once. Samples were homogenized in sterile bags and a subsample was immediate placed on dry ice for DNA extraction. The remaining sample was placed on “blue” ice (4 °C) and refrigerated in the laboratory for 2 days until the laboratory incubation experiment. The remaining field-collected soils were air-dried and ground to a fine powder using mortar and pestle. Approximately 10 mg of oven-dry, ground soil was weighed into tin capsules, and these samples were analyzed for total carbon (C) and nitrogen (N) by continuous-flow, direct combustion and mass spectrometry using the ECS 4010 CHNSO analyzer (Costech Analytical Technologies, Inc., Valencia, CA, USA) at the University of California Merced Stable Isotope Laboratory (https://research.ucmerced.edu/core-facilities/stable-isotope-laboratory).</para></description>      </methodStep><methodStep>        <description><para>Step 2: Laboratory nutrient amendment incubation experiment</para><para>We conducted a laboratory incubation experiment with the collected soils. Upon returning to the laboratory, soils from the 10-30 cm (representing “surface soils,” mix of A and AB genetic horizons) and from the 60-80 cm depths (representing “subsoils”, Bt genetic horizon) were split into 5-g subsamples. Each of these subsamples were then placed in 35 ml centrifuge tubes and given either a C, C + nutrient, or control amendment in a 0.4 ml solution. These amendments represented ~10 times the microbial C and N and ~20 times the microbial P found in these soils. We doubled the amount of P to account for P sorption onto mineral surfaces. As such, surface aliquots received: 15 mg cellobiose-C and 4.82 mg NaCl (+C); 1.75 mg NH4Cl-N, 0.5 mg NaH2PO4-P, and 15 mg cellobiose-C (+CNP); or 4.82 mg NaCl (control). Sodium chloride was given to the +C and control treatments to account for the mass of Na+ and Cl- ions in the +CNP treatment and to create osmotically similar solutions. Subsoil subsamples were given the same amendments but at levels 23% of the surface soil, commensurate with microbial biomass differences between these two depths. Subsamples were covered loosely with Parafilm to minimize moisture loss while allowing for gas exchange. Soils from heated and control plots were separated and placed into two different incubators (Series KB 240, Binder Group LP, Camarillo, CA, USA) set to 14 and 10 °C, respectively, corresponding to the average temperatures of the field experiment at the time of sampling.</para></description>      </methodStep><methodStep>        <description><para>Step 3: Chemical analysis of incubation experiments</para><para>We measured microbial respiration at 1, 3, 8, 16, and 28 days of the incubations after the amendment addition. Four subsamples from each amendment × temperature × depth × replicate combination were uncovered and placed in a 500 ml wide-mouth screw-top jar fitted with a butyl rubber septum. We immediately sampled 16 ml of headspace and placed the jars in their respective incubators. We again sampled 16 ml of headspace after 6 h to determine the hourly respiration rate, and subsamples were removed from each jar and re-covered with Parafilm. We used the same subsamples for respiration measurements throughout the incubation. Headspace samples were then analyzed for carbon dioxide by gas chromatography using a Shimadzu GC-2014 equipped with a thermal conductivity detector (Shimadzu Corporation, Columbia, MD, USA). Cumulative gas fluxes were determined by integrating the rates at different times throughout the incubation over the course of 28 days.</para><para>We determined N availability by net N mineralization during our 30-d incubation. Briefly, inorganic N pool sizes before and after the 30-day incubation were determined by extracting a 5-g soil subsamples with 25 mL of 2 M KCl. Extracts were analyzed for ammonium (Lachat method: 12-107-06-1-B) and nitrate (Lachat method: 10-107-04-1-A) colorimetrically using the Lachat AE Flow Injection Auto analyzer (Lachat Instruments, Inc., Milwaukee, WI, USA). Net N mineralization rates were determined by the net changes in inorganic N pools over the 30-day incubation period.</para><para>We used the 13C isotopologue-metabolic modeling approach to measure carbon use efficiency (CUE) (Dijkstra et al., 2011) at the end of the laboratory incubation. Briefly, four aliquots per replicate of each treatment were given one of four 2.5 mM, 0.5 ml amendments: 1-13C pyruvate; 2,3-13C pyruvate; 1-13C glucose; or U-13C glucose as metabolic tracers. Each aliquot was placed in a 500 ml wide-mouth Mason jar fitted with a butyl rubber septum. After 2 h for surface soils and 12 h for subsoils (because of slower metabolic rates at depth), we sampled 25 ml of headspace into an evacuated 20 ml vial. These samples were then analyzed for 13CO2 concentrations using a G2131-i Cavity Ring Down Spectrometer CO2 Isotope and Concentration Analyzer equipped with a Small Sample Isotope Module (Picarro Inc., Santa Clara, CA, USA). The ratios between 13CO2 production rates from glucose and pyruvate isotopologues were calculated and used to model C allocated for energy production or biosynthesis.</para></description>      </methodStep>                      </methods><project id="9cc37650-e339-4174-b9ba-a659d6fb244c" scope="system" system="ess-dive">      <title>Belowground Biogeochemistry Scientific Focus Area</title>      <personnel>        <individualName>          <givenName>Margaret</givenName>          <surName>Torn</surName>        </individualName>        <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>        <electronicMailAddress>mstorn@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>        <role>Principal Investigator</role>      </personnel>    </project><otherEntity id="ess-dive-f5b7a88900f8435-20220324T211119541">      <entityName>soilChemistry.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-3b31f9e729ae4c4-20220324T211119537">      <entityName>soilChemistry___dd.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-25db03ab3913b8c-20220429T175757653">      <entityName>incubationData.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-0b9549318524178-20220324T211119509">      <entityName>dataFiles_flmd.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-e10da5042b6fba4-20220324T211119529">      <entityName>incubationData___dd.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity>                                      </dataset></eml:eml>