<?xml version="1.0"?><eml:eml xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.1" system="ess-dive" xsi:schemaLocation="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0 https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0/eml.xsd" packageId="ess-dive-d18cbfe76b8c319-20230504T210147458052">  <dataset id="dataset.id">    <alternateIdentifier>paf_739_742</alternateIdentifier>    <title>Sensor-based phenology from snowmelt experiment gradient, East River, Colorado, 2017 to 2020</title>    <creator id="1711334350041635">      <individualName>        <givenName>Heidi</givenName>        <surName>Steltzer</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Fort Lewis College</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>steltzer_h@fortlewis.edu</electronicMailAddress>      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-5199-9932</userId>    </creator>    <creator id="2596422390069008">      <individualName>        <givenName>Amanda</givenName>        <surName>Henderson</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Rocky Mountain Biological Laboratory</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>amanda.henderson3@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-9613-5003</userId>    </creator>    <creator id="2494824135019835">      <individualName>        <givenName>Chelsea</givenName>        <surName>Wilmer</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Colorado State University</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>chelsea.f.wilmer@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-5244-4824</userId>    </creator>    <associatedParty id="7734937487376562">      <organizationName>U.S. DOE &gt; Office of Science &gt; Biological and Environmental Research (BER)</organizationName>      <userId directory="unknown">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/100006206</userId>      <role>fundingOrganization</role>    </associatedParty>    <pubDate>2021</pubDate>    <abstract>      <para>The timing of snowmelt is a critical cue for the initiation of growth in mountain meadow ecosystems and can also impact the duration and magnitude of plant production. High frequency observations of species-level phenology are time consuming and require a high degree of expertise, and publicly available remote sensing products lack the necessary temporal resolution to assess fine-scale growing season dynamics. Near-surface sensing methods provide a middle ground with high temporal frequency and tractable spatial scales (from sub-meter to hillslope scale). This data package includes csv files of Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI) timeseries (SM_NDVI_dailymax.csv) and phenological thresholds (SM_NDVI_summary.csv) for sub-plots (1m2) and Green Chromatic Coordinate (GCC) phenological thresholds (SM_GCC_summary.csv) at the plot scale (10m x 14m). Location IDs associated with this data package are: ER-LM, WG-UM, WG-LS, ER-US, and XX-AL. Related data packages include: “Microclimate observations associated with snowmelt experiment gradient sites, East River, Colorado, 2017 to 2020” and “Colorado Elevation Gradient Snowmelt Manipulation Plant Phenology 2017-2018”.</para>    </abstract>    <keywordSet>      <keyword> growing season</keyword>      <keyword>Green Chromatic Coordinate</keyword>      <keyword>Normalized Difference Vegetation Index</keyword>      <keywordThesaurus>CATEGORICAL:NONE</keywordThesaurus>    </keywordSet>    <keywordSet>      <keyword>Phenology</keyword>      <keyword>NDVI</keyword>      <keywordThesaurus>VARIABLE:NONE</keywordThesaurus>    </keywordSet>    <additionalInfo>      <section>        <title>Related References</title>        <para>Additional metadata on specific locations within the watershed are provided in the following related data package:</para>        <para>Varadharajan C ; Kakalia Z ; Banfield J ; Berkelhammer M ; Brodie E ; Christianson D ; Dafflon B ; Carbone M S ; Carroll R ; Chadwick K D ; Christensen J ; Enquist B J ; Fox P ; Henderson M ; Gochis D ; Kueppers L ; Powell T ; Matheus Carnevali P ; Singha K ; Sorensen P ; Tokunaga T ; Versteeg R ; Wilkins M ; Williams K ; Worsham M ; Wu Y ; Agarwal D (2020): Location Identifiers, Metadata, and Map for Field Measurements at the East River Watershed, Colorado, USA. Watershed Function SFA. doi:10.15485/1660962</para>        <para>Wilmer C ; Steltzer H (2021): Colorado Elevation Gradient Snowmelt Manipulation Plant Phenology 2017-2018. Watershed Function SFA, ESS-DIVE repository. Dataset. doi:10.15485/1842905 accessed via https://data.ess-dive.lbl.gov/datasets/doi:10.15485/1842905 on 2022-02-01</para>        <para>Steltzer H ; Wilmer C ; Henderson A (2021): Microclimate observations associated with snowmelt experiment gradient sites, East River, Colorado, 2017 to 2020. Watershed Function SFA, ESS-DIVE repository. Dataset. doi:10.15485/1842907 accessed via https://data.ess-dive.lbl.gov/datasets/doi:10.15485/1842907 on 2022-02-01</para>      </section>    </additionalInfo>    <intellectualRights>      <para>This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, visit http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/.</para>    </intellectualRights>    <coverage>      <geographicCoverage>        <geographicDescription>The East River (ER) is a snow‐dominated, headwater basin of the Upper Colorado River Basin (UCRB) located in the western United States. The ER is the designated testbed of Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory's Watershed Function Scientific Focus Area (WFSFA). Through WFSFA, observational networks have been established to measure stream discharge and precipitation chemistry. The ER is considered representative of many snow‐dominated headwaters of the Rocky Mountains. The study domain encompasses nearly 85 square km, a 1.4‐km vertical drop in elevation (4,120 to 2,760 m) and pristine alpine, subalpine, montane, and riparian ecosystems. The ER contains high‐energy mountain streams to low‐energy meandering floodplains and is eroding primarily into the Cretaceous, carbon‐rich, marine shale of the Mancos Formation. Additional metadata on specific locations within the watershed are provided in the following related data package: Varadharajan C. et al. (2020) doi:10.15485/1660962</geographicDescription>        <boundingCoordinates>          <westBoundingCoordinate>-107.05</westBoundingCoordinate>          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-106.88</eastBoundingCoordinate>          <northBoundingCoordinate>39.034</northBoundingCoordinate>          <southBoundingCoordinate>38.88</southBoundingCoordinate>        </boundingCoordinates>      </geographicCoverage>      <temporalCoverage>        <rangeOfDates>          <beginDate>            <calendarDate>2017-05-26</calendarDate>          </beginDate>          <endDate>            <calendarDate>2020-09-27</calendarDate>          </endDate>        </rangeOfDates>      </temporalCoverage>    </coverage>    <contact id="7728867589483319">      <individualName>        <givenName>Heidi</givenName>        <surName>Steltzer</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Fort Lewis College</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>steltzer_h@fortlewis.edu</electronicMailAddress>      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-5199-9932</userId>    </contact>    <methods>      <methodStep>        <description>          <para>Sub-plot based NDVI was monitored via a combination of upward and downward facing light sensors. The incoming light environment was quantified from sensors measuring solar radiation (SR, 300 - 1100 nm) and photosynthetically active radiation (PAR, 400 – 700 nm). SR and PAR sensors were also placed facing downward approximately 50cm above the top of canopy to quantify broadband NDVI (see Sweet et al. 2015 for full methods). Measurements were filtered to only include four hours around solar noon (1100 to 1500 MDT) and clear sky conditions (incoming SR &gt; 1000 W m-2). NDVI timeseries were processed using the phenopix R package and were smoothed using cubic spline, and thresholds were extracted for onset of peak (75% maximum NDVI), peak timing, and end of season (75% maximum NDVI on the falling limb).</para>          <para>GCC was calculated from timelapse cameras (Moultrie M40) mounted on t-posts installed on the uphill edge of each plot. Camera angle was adjusted using a hinged mount and was typically 45° in order to capture the majority of each 10m x 14m plot (actual camera angle dictated by microtopography). Calculation of GCC and filtering were done using the phenopix R package, as well as smoothing and threshold extraction described above.</para>        </description>      </methodStep>    </methods>    <project id="024b867d-25e3-4025-b68c-6598aded7aa2" scope="system" system="ess-dive">      <title>Watershed Function SFA</title>      <personnel>        <individualName>          <givenName>Eoin</givenName>          <surName>Brodie</surName>        </individualName>        <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>        <electronicMailAddress>elbrodie@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>        <role>Principal Investigator</role>      </personnel>    </project>    <otherEntity id="ess-dive-ab6f2acfbd13962-20211207T203804553354">      <entityName>SM_NDVI_dailymax.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity>    <otherEntity id="ess-dive-baa12e95d64a237-20211207T203803672304">      <entityName>SM_GCC_summary.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity>    <otherEntity id="ess-dive-8f23ef1ec85f03e-20211207T203806491098">      <entityName>SM_NDVI_summary.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity>  </dataset></eml:eml>