<?xml version="1.0"?><eml:eml xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.1" system="ess-dive" xsi:schemaLocation="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0 https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0/eml.xsd" packageId="ess-dive-c021aed75d34053-20230808T232255271">  <dataset id="dataset.id"><title>Kinetic and temperature sensitivity properties of soil exoenzymes through the soil profile down to one-meter depth at a temperate coniferous forest (Blodgett, CA)</title><creator id="1476526848184182">      <individualName><givenName>Ricardo J Eloy</givenName><surName>Alves</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>rjealves@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-7567-3205</userId>    </creator><creator id="5374409916608525">      <individualName><givenName>Ileana A</givenName><surName>Callejas</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, University of California Los Angeles</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>iacallejas@ucla.edu</electronicMailAddress>                </creator><creator id="8655289162485012">      <individualName><givenName>Gianna L</givenName><surName>Marschmann</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>glmarschmann@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-9065-2023</userId>    </creator><creator id="5967674426687813">      <individualName><givenName>Maria</givenName><surName>Mooshammer</surName></individualName><organizationName>University of California  Berkeley</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>maria.mooshammer@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-6631-7321</userId>    </creator><creator id="5335412345240676">      <individualName><givenName>Hans W</givenName><surName>Singh</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, University of California  Berkeley</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>hwsingh@ucsd.edu</electronicMailAddress>                </creator><creator id="4837635571534345">      <individualName><givenName>Bizuayehu</givenName><surName>Whitney</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, University of California  Berkeley</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>bizwhitney300@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>                </creator><creator id="5944611125514862">      <individualName><givenName>Margaret S</givenName><surName>Torn</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>mstorn@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8174-0099</userId>    </creator><creator id="1154774079673988">      <individualName><givenName>Eoin L</givenName><surName>Brodie</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>elbrodie@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8453-8435</userId>    </creator><associatedParty id="3887613498551235"><organizationName>US.DOE. &#x3E; Office of Science &#x3E; Biological and Environmental Research (BER)</organizationName>            <role>fundingOrganization</role>    </associatedParty><pubDate>2021</pubDate>                                                <abstract><para>This dataset contains data on kinetic and temperature sensitivity parameters of the exoenzymes β-glucosidase (BG), leucine/leucyl aminopeptidase (LAP) and acid phosphatase (AP) across a soil profile down to 90 cm depth at Blodgett forest, CA, USA. These data were generated to determine if kinetic and thermal properties of microbial exoenzymes involved in organic matter decomposition varied with soil depth, following variation in soil properties and microbial communities, as part of the study: Alves et al. (2021). Kinetic Properties of Microbial Exoenzymes Vary with Soil Depth but Have Similar Temperature Sensitivities Through the Soil Profile. Frontiers in Microbiology 12:3618. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2021.735282. This research was performed within the framework of the TES Belowground Biogeochemistry SFA project, in particular association with a long-term field warming experiment of the whole soil profile at Blodgett forest. Samples for this work were collected from locations representative of the field experimental plots.</para><para>Potential enzyme activity rates were measured using laboratory fluorometric assays with soils collected at 0-10, 10-20, 30-40, 50-60, 60-70 and 80-90 cm deep in biological triplicates (i.e., three soil cores collected at different representative locations). Assays with each soil were conducted over a gradient of eight substrate concentrations per enzyme, and incubated at 4, 10, 16, 25, 35 or 50°C. Enzyme Michaelis-Menten kinetics were modeled over the eight substrate concentrations at each temperature, and the temperature sensitivity of the kinetic parameters was modeled over the six temperatures using linear Arrhenius/Q10 and non-linear Macromolecular Rate Theory (MMRT) models.</para><para>The dataset includes the fully processed enzyme activity rate data used to model Michaelis-Menten kinetics, calculated kinetic and temperature sensitivity parameters, and basic soil and microbial biomass chemistry for each sample. All data is provided for each individual biological replicate, and kinetic and temperature sensitivity parameters are also provided as means of the biological replicates. The dataset also includes all raw measurement data and code used to parse, combine and perform the analyses described by Alves et al. (2021). For file descriptions, see the file-level metadata files: “enzymes_dataProcessed_flmd.xlsx” (processed data); “enzymes_dataRaw_flmd.xlsx” (compressed raw data and metadata); and “enzymes_code_flmd.xlsx” (compressed code). The experimental design, list of parameters measured, soil and microbial biomass chemistry data, and means of biological replicates for kinetic and temperature sensitivity parameters are also provided as human-readable tables in file “enzymeTraits_design_results_tables.xlsx”.</para></abstract><keywordSet><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; SUBSOILS</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ORGANIC MATTER</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; MICROBIAL TRAITS</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; EXTRACELLULAR ENZYMES</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME KINETICS</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME TEMPERATURE SENSITIVITY</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME Q10</keyword><keyword>MACROMOLECULAR RATE THEORY</keyword><keyword>ARRHENIUS</keyword><keyword>MICHAELIS-MENTEN</keyword><keyword>ESS-DIVE Sample ID and Metadata Reporting Format</keyword><keyword>ESS-DIVE CSV File Formatting Guidelines Reporting Format</keyword><keyword>ESS-DIVE File Level Metadata Reporting Format</keyword><keywordThesaurus>CATEGORICAL:NONE</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet><keywordSet><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS</keyword><keywordThesaurus>CATEGORICAL:GCMD</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet><keywordSet><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; MICROBIAL BIOMASS CARBON</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; MICROBIAL BIOMASS NITROGEN</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME ACTIVITY RATE</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME MAXIMUM VELOCITY VMAX</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME HALF-SATURATION CONSTANT KM</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME CATALYTIC EFFICIENCY</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME TEMPERATURE COEFFICIENT Q10</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME POINT OF MAXIMUM TEMPERATURE SENSITIVITY TSMAX</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME TEMPERATURE OPTIMUM TOPT</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME CHANGE IN HEAT CAPACITY ΔCp‡</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; ENZYME ACTIVATION ENERGY EA</keyword><keywordThesaurus>VARIABLE:NONE</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet><keywordSet><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; SOIL MOISTURE/WATER CONTENT</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; SOIL DEPTH</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; CARBON</keyword><keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &#x3E; LAND SURFACE &#x3E; SOILS &#x3E; NITROGEN</keyword><keywordThesaurus>VARIABLE:GCMD</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet>                    <additionalInfo><section><title>Related References</title><para>Associated paper describing the data analysis:Alves, R. J. E., Callejas, I. A., Marschmann, G. L., Mooshammer, M., Singh, H. W., Whitney, B., Torn, M. S., Brodie, E. L. (2021). Kinetic Properties of Microbial Exoenzymes Vary with Soil Depth but Have Similar Temperature Sensitivities Through the Soil Profile. Front. Microbiol. 12:3618. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2021.735282</para><para>Allison, S. D., Romero-Olivares, A. L., Lu, Y., Taylor, J. W., and Treseder, K. K. (2018). Temperature sensitivities of extracellular enzyme Vmax and Km across thermal environments. Glob. Chang. Biol. 24, 2884–2897. https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.14045</para><para>Alster, C. J., Koyama, A., Johnson, N. G., Wallenstein, M. D., and von Fischer, J. C. (2016). Temperature sensitivity of soil microbial communities: An application of macromolecular rate theory to microbial respiration. J. Geophys. Res. Biogeosciences 121, 1420–1433. https://doi.org/10.1002/2016JG003343</para><para>Alster, C. J., von Fischer, J. C., Allison, S. D., and Treseder, K. K. (2020). Embracing a new paradigm for temperature sensitivity of soil microbes. Glob. Chang. Biol. 26, 3221–3229. https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.15053</para><para>Brookes, P. C., Landman, A., Pruden, G., and Jenkinson, D. S. (1985). Chloroform fumigation and the release of soil nitrogen: A rapid direct extraction method to measure microbial biomass nitrogen in soil. Soil Biol. Biochem. 17, 837–842. https://doi.org/10.1016/0038-0717(85)90144-0</para><para>German, D. P., Weintraub, M. N., Grandy, A. S., Lauber, C. L., Rinkes, Z. L., and Allison, S. D. (2011). Optimization of hydrolytic and oxidative enzyme methods for ecosystem studies. Soil Biol. Biochem. 43, 1387–1397. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soilbio.2011.03.017</para><para>Hicks Pries, C. E., Castanha, C., Porras, R. C., Torn, M. S. (2017). The whole-soil carbon flux in response to warming. Science 355, 1420–1423. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aal1319</para><para>Hicks Pries, C. E., Sulman, B. N., West, C., O'Neill, C., Poppleton, E., Porras, R. C., Castanha, C., Zhu, B., Wiedemeier, D. B., Torn, M. S. (2018). Root litter decomposition slows with soil depth. Soil Biol. Biochem. 125, 103–114. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soilbio.2018.07.002.</para><para>R Core Team (2020). R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. Available at: https://www.r-project.org/</para><para>Ritz, C., Baty, F., Streibig, J. C., and Gerhard, D. (2015). Dose-response analysis using R. PLoS One 10, e0146021. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0146021</para><para>Soong, J. L., Castanha, C., Hicks Pries, C. E., Ofiti, N., Porras, R. C., Riley, W. J., Schmidt, M. W., Torn, M. S. (2021). Five years of whole-soil warming led to loss of subsoil carbon stocks and increased CO2 efflux. Sci. Adv. 7, eabd1343. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.abd1343</para></section></additionalInfo>    <intellectualRights><para>This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, visit http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/.</para></intellectualRights>    <coverage>      <geographicCoverage>        <geographicDescription>Samples were collected at the University of California Blodgett Experimental Forest, Sierra Nevada, CA, where a long-term warming experiment of the soil profile down to one-meter depth is ongoing since 2014 (see Hicks Pries et al., 2017 and Soong et al., 2021). Soil samples used to generate the present data were collected approximately in-between heated (4°C above ambient temperature) and unheated control plots of the warming experiment, at a location unaffected by the heaters. The site has been described in detail by Hicks Pries et al. (2018). Briefly, Blodgett forest is located in a Mediterranean climate with mean annual precipitation of 1,660 mm and a mean annual air temperature of 12.5°C. The soil was classified as Alfisol of granitic origin, and has a developed O horizon. The site is a mixed coniferous forest with ponderosa pine (Pinus ponderosa), sugar pine (Pinus lambertiana), incense cedar (Calodefrus decurrens), white fir (Abies concolor) and douglas fir (Pseudotsuga menziesii) as dominant tree species. The mean annual soil temperature ranges between 11.5 and 10.4°C at 5 and 100 cm depths, respectively, although soil temperatures vary annually between 0-29°C, 1-19°C and 2-16°C at 5, 30 and 100 cm depth, respectively.</geographicDescription>        <boundingCoordinates><westBoundingCoordinate>-120.66</westBoundingCoordinate><eastBoundingCoordinate>-120.66</eastBoundingCoordinate><northBoundingCoordinate>38.912</northBoundingCoordinate><southBoundingCoordinate>38.912</southBoundingCoordinate></boundingCoordinates>      </geographicCoverage>      <temporalCoverage><rangeOfDates><beginDate><calendarDate>2019-07-09</calendarDate></beginDate><endDate><calendarDate>2019-08-09</calendarDate></endDate></rangeOfDates></temporalCoverage>    </coverage><contact id="6768180551504599">      <individualName><givenName>Ricardo J Eloy</givenName><surName>Alves</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>rjealves@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>                  <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-7567-3205</userId>    </contact><publisher id="2962281324392222">          <organizationName>Terrestrial Ecosystem Science at Berkeley Lab</organizationName></publisher><methods><methodStep>        <description><para>All steps adapted from: Alves et al. (2021). Kinetic Properties of Microbial Exoenzymes Vary with Soil Depth but Have Similar Temperature Sensitivities Through the Soil Profile. Front. Microbiol. 12:3618. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2021.735282</para><para>Sample Collection</para><para>Three soil cores were collected using a 4.78 cm diameter soil corer with a 10 kg hand-held slide-hammer. The surface litter layer of the O horizon was removed prior to sampling, and mineral soil samples were recovered sequentially in 10 cm increments down to 90 cm depth. Samples were kept cold during transportation to the laboratory, were they were sieved to 2 mm and stored at 4°C. Samples were analyzed within approximately a week of collection.</para></description>      </methodStep><methodStep>        <description><para>Exoenzyme Activity Assays</para><para>Extracellular hydrolytic enzyme activities were determined fluorometrically according to standard assays (German et al., 2011) in soils collected at six depth intervals: 0-10, 10-20, 30-40, 50-60, 60-70 and 80-90 cm deep. We used the methylumbelliferone (MUF)-linked substrates MUF-β-D-glucopyranoside and MUF-phosphate for determination of β-glucosidase (BG) and acid phosphatase (AP) activities, respectively. Leucine aminopeptidase (LAP) activity was determined using the substrate L-leucine-7-amido-4methylcoumarin (AMC). Assays were performed for each of the six soil depths from each of three replicate soil cores, by combining 200 µL of soil homogenate with 50 µL of fluorogenic substrate solution in each microplate well. Soil homogenates were prepared with 1 g of fresh soil in 100 mL 50 mM acetate buffer with pH 5.5, by mixing with a regular blender. The same buffer was used to prepare all substrate solutions, soil homogenates, serial dilutions of standards in the absence or presence of soil homogenate (quenching controls), blank quenching controls without standards, and blank controls in the absence or presence of each of the eight substrate concentrations. Standards in the presence or absence of soil homogenates (quenched standards) were prepared over six 1:10 serial dilutions, from 0.625 to 20 µM for MUF, and 0.3125 to 10 µM for AMC. MUF and AMC standards without soil homogenates, blank controls with only substrates, and blank quenching controls with soil homogenates, but no MUF or AMC standards, were performed in duplicate. Each enzyme was assayed individually over a range of eight substrate concentrations, as follows: 10, 30, 60, 100, 150, 250, 450 and 800 µM for BG; 10, 20, 40, 70, 110, 190, 350 and 600 µM for LAP; and 10, 40, 80, 130, 200, 350, 700 and 1200 µM for AP. Parallel assays for each sample, enzyme and substrate concentration were performed in black microplates individually covered with lids to avoid evaporation, and incubated in the dark at 4, 10, 16, 25, 35 or 50°C. Fluorescence was recorded (excitation: 365 nm, and emission: 450 nm) after approximately 1, 4 and 24 h to determine the optimal incubation time. Four analytical replicates were measured per sample for each combination of enzyme, substrate concentration and temperature. A set of standards, and blank, substrate and quenching controls was incubated together with each batch of assays at each temperature, to correct fluorescence measurements for temperature-specific effects in the assays. Incubation temperatures were selected in order to capture the unimodal response predicted by MMRT with Topt values well above native temperatures, as observed by previous studies of exoenzymes from temperate environments (Alster et al., 2016), while including the temperature range and approximate seasonal averages at our experimental site.</para></description>      </methodStep><methodStep>        <description><para>Microbial Biomass C and Dissolved C and N Pools</para><para>Microbial biomass C (MBC), dissolved organic C (DOC) and total dissolved N (TDN) were determined at every 10 cm depth interval between 0-90 cm depth. MBC was estimated using the chloroform-fumigation extraction method (Brookes et al., 1985). Five-gram soil samples were fumigated in 50 mL closed vials containing a jumbo cotton ball soaked with ethanol-free chloroform over, but not touching, the soil, for 7 days, with chloroform replenished on day 4. Fumigated and a non-fumigated soil samples were extracted with 25 mL of 0.5 M K2SO4 on an orbital shaker table for 60 min, then gravity filtered through pre-leached #42 Whatman filter paper, and frozen until further analysis. DOC and TDN in fumigated and non-fumigated samples were quantified using a Lotix Combustion TOC/TN Analyzer (Teledyne Tekmar, Mason, Ohio, USA). No correction factor (kEC) was applied to account for incomplete microbial biomass lysis during the fumigation.</para></description>      </methodStep><methodStep>        <description><para>Data Analyses</para><para>All data manipulations and analyses were performed in R versions 3.6.1-4.0.4 (R Core Team, 2020). Net fluorescence in the enzyme assays, including quenching corrections, were calculated following German et al. (2011). Negative values due to analytical error were excluded from the dataset (0.8%); analytical outliers were further identified based on the Interquartile Range method, and a maximum of one value was excluded out of the four analytical replicates per sample. In total, these procedures excluded 1917 out of 26784 data-points (7.2%). Enzyme maximal velocity (Vmax) and Michaelis constants (Km) were computed by fitting a 2-parameter Michaelis-Menten (MM) model over all analytical replicates of each of eight substrate concentrations using the drm function in the drc package (Ritz et al., 2015), with a data-driven self-starter function specific to the model. Following preliminary analyses, and when necessary, we excluded data points corresponding to one of the eight individual substrate concentrations for which all analytical replicates consistently did not fit the distribution of the remaining data (i.e., due to inhibition at high concentrations or technical errors during assay preparation). In order to alleviate variance heterogeneity of analytical replicates between substrate concentrations, we applied a Box-Cox transformation to all models using the boxcox function in the drc package (Ritz et al., 2015). Comparison between the parameters Vmax and Km estimated based on transformed and non-transformed models showed that Box-Cox transformation improved the fit of models with substantial analytical variance, but had a marginal or no effect on parameters estimated by models with initial good fit. Individual models yielding nonsignificant Vmax or Km estimates (p &#x3E; 0.05) after Box-Cox transformation were considered to have bad fit and were thus excluded from further analyses (excluded 11 out of 324 models). To determine the optimal assay incubation time at each temperature, we compared MM models fit to data collected after each of three sequential incubation periods (1, 4 and 24 h). We selected the minimum incubation period necessary to reach the highest Vmax value, under the assumptions that lower Vmax values reflected either insufficient incubation time for reactions to reach saturation, decrease in activity, or loss of fluorescence due to prolonged incubation after saturation had been reached. The same incubation period was consistently selected for each batch of assays performed at the same temperature. Vmax was expressed per mass of dry soil as Vmax/ds (nmol g-1 h-1) and per unit of microbial biomass C (MBC) as Vmax/MBC (nmol µg MBC-1 h-1). The apparent catalytic efficiency (CEds) was calculated as:</para><para>Vmax/ds/Km</para><para>and the biomass-specific catalytic efficiency (CEMBC) as:</para><para>Vmax/MBC/Km</para><para>Q10 coefficients were calculated over the full experimental temperature range (six temperatures from 4 to 50°C) and over a realistic field range (five temperatures from 4 to 35°C) following the approach by Allison et al. (2018). Briefly, the degree of change in Vmax, Km or CE per °C was inferred based on linear regressions between the natural logarithm of each parameter and temperature, and converted to Q10 values based on the relationship:</para><para>Q10=exp⁡(10×slope)</para><para>The Arrhenius activation energy (Ea) was calculated based on the slope of the linear regression between ln(Vmax) and 1/T, and the relationship:</para><para>-Ea=slope×R</para><para>where T is the temperature in kelvin and R is the universal gas constant. Linear regression models were calculated using the lm function in the stats package native to R (R Core Team, 2020). The change in heat capacity (ΔCp‡), temperature optimum (Topt) and point of maximum temperature sensitivity (TSmax) were calculated by fitting ln(Vmax) over the six incubation temperatures between 4-50°C using the Macromolecular Rate Theory (MMRT) model, according to the equations and definitions described by Alster et al. (2020). The reference temperature T0 was set to 315 K to best match the measured data, following the recommendations by Alster et al. (2020).</para></description>      </methodStep><methodStep>        <description><para>This section provides a list of source material physical samples used in the dataset, specifically parent sediment core samples. More information describing the samples is provided in sample landing pages (links below) and the enzymes_sampleMetadata.xls dataset file.</para><para>Sample Name	        IGSN PID	                                IGSN URL</para><para>BE201907091COP	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE009U	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE009U</para><para>BE201907092COP	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE009V	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE009V</para><para>BE201907093COP	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE009W	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE009W</para></description>      </methodStep><methodStep>        <description><para>This section provides a list of source material physical samples used in the dataset, specifically child sediment core samples. More information describing the samples is provided in sample landing pages (links below) and the enzymes_sampleMetadata.xls dataset file.</para><para>Sample Name	IGSN PID	IGSN URL</para><para>BE201907091COP0010	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE009X	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE009X</para><para>BE201907091COP1020	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE009Y	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE009Y</para><para>BE201907091COP2030	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE009Z	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE009Z</para><para>BE201907091COP3040	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00A0	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00A0</para><para>BE201907091COP4050	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00A1	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00A1</para><para>BE201907091COP5060	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00A2	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00A2</para><para>BE201907091COP6070	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00A3	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00A3</para><para>BE201907091COP7080	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00A4	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00A4</para><para>BE201907091COP8090	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00A5	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00A5</para><para>BE201907092COP0010	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00A6	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00A6</para><para>BE201907092COP1020	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00A7	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00A7</para><para>BE201907092COP2030	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00A8	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00A8</para><para>BE201907092COP3040	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00A9	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00A9</para><para>BE201907092COP4050	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AA	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AA</para><para>BE201907092COP5060	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AB	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AB</para><para>BE201907092COP6070	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AC	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AC</para><para>BE201907092COP7080	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AD	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AD</para><para>BE201907092COP8090	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AE	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AE</para><para>BE201907093COP0010	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AF	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AF</para><para>BE201907093COP1020	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AG	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AG</para><para>BE201907093COP2030	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AH	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AH</para><para>BE201907093COP3040	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AI	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AI</para><para>BE201907093COP4050	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AJ	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AJ</para><para>BE201907093COP5060	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AK	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AK</para><para>BE201907093COP6070	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AL	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AL</para><para>BE201907093COP7080	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AM	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AM</para><para>BE201907093COP8090	IGSN:10.58052/IEBWE00AN	https://doi.org/10.58052/IEBWE00AN</para></description>      </methodStep>                                        </methods><project id="9cc37650-e339-4174-b9ba-a659d6fb244c" scope="system" system="ess-dive">      <title>Belowground Biogeochemistry Scientific Focus Area</title>      <personnel>        <individualName>          <givenName>Margaret</givenName>          <surName>Torn</surName>        </individualName>        <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>        <electronicMailAddress>mstorn@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>        <role>Principal Investigator</role>      </personnel>    </project><otherEntity id="ess-dive-9d92e2beafde496-20211110T033225813">      <entityName>soilChemistry.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-e3bb183cb3b376c-20211110T033225808">      <entityName>soilChemistry_dd.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-78bff79a63479e1-20211110T033225782">      <entityName>enzymes_dataRaw.zip</entityName>      <entityType>application/zip</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-7419e115ee5fe9f-20211110T033225804">      <entityName>enzymeTraits_design_results_tables.xlsx</entityName>      <entityType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-1cbc72a852a19da-20211110T033225800">      <entityName>enzymeTempSens_corr.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-e852f9e0f15876d-20211110T033225742">      <entityName>enzymeKinetics_corr___dd.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-f8ac25d8c165aec-20211110T033225766">      <entityName>enzymes_code.zip</entityName>      <entityType>application/zip</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-35c6629f6f9fd5d-20211110T033225753">      <entityName>enzymeKinetics_corr.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-c6e3a53e85d97c5-20211110T033225737">      <entityName>enzymeActivity_corr.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-f0c6b3ce1934d86-20211110T033225795">      <entityName>enzymeTempSens_corr_means.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-592bf6d5e33e2ff-20211110T033225791">      <entityName>enzymeTempSens_corr___dd.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-6a4730e690e5063-20211110T033225721">      <entityName>enzymeActivity_corr_dd.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-c1acaad05b281c3-20211110T033225747">      <entityName>enzymeKinetics_corr_means.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-c6ac6ef2bf743ee-20211111T202459720">      <entityName>enzymes_dataRaw_flmd.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-d4916e0f7fa879d-20220201T175547209">      <entityName>enzymes_dataProcessed_flmd.xlsx</entityName>      <entityType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-36e5291d019100d-20220201T175552878">      <entityName>enzymes_dataProcessed_flmd.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-4335b203061d886-20211111T202459696">      <entityName>enzymes_code_flmd.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-e6371950cae3943-20211111T202459737">      <entityName>enzymes_sampleMetadata.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-af22c0dbc64ea9a-20211111T202459744">      <entityName>enzymes_sampleMetadata.xls</entityName>      <entityType>application/vnd.ms-excel</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-3accae43a3dce06-20211111T202459729">      <entityName>enzymes_dataRaw_flmd.xlsx</entityName>      <entityType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</entityType>    </otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-6e19a109989b1f5-20211111T202459675">      <entityName>enzymes_code_flmd.xlsx</entityName>      <entityType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</entityType>    </otherEntity>                                                                                                      </dataset></eml:eml>