<?xml version="1.0"?><eml:eml xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.1" system="ess-dive" xsi:schemaLocation="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0 https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0/eml.xsd" packageId="ess-dive-016ac7f7109133b-20230407T145927814145">  <dataset id="dataset.id">    <title>C fluxes from incubations of California upland soil with and without synthetic iron (hydr)oxide associations</title>    <creator id="6470220338902439">      <individualName>        <givenName>Rachel</givenName>        <surName>Porras</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>rcporras@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>    <creator id="4808292601649407">      <individualName>        <givenName>Caitlin</givenName>        <surName>Hicks Pries</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Dartmouth College</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>Caitlin.Hicks.Pries@dartmouth.edu</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>    <creator id="6393404589826558">      <individualName>        <givenName>Peter</givenName>        <surName>Nico</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>psnico@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>    <creator id="8312937892525686">      <individualName>        <givenName>Margaret</givenName>        <surName>Torn</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>mstorn@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>    <associatedParty id="4935687187235802">      <individualName>        <givenName>Cristina</givenName>        <surName>Castanha</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>ccastanha@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>      <role>contributor</role>    </associatedParty>    <associatedParty id="9225391584241108">      <organizationName>U.S. DOE &gt; Office of Science &gt; Biological and Environmental Research (BER)</organizationName>      <userId directory="unknown">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/100006206</userId>      <role>fundingOrganization</role>    </associatedParty>    <pubDate>2022</pubDate>    <abstract>      <para>There is a growing understanding that interactions with soil mineral phases contribute to the accumulation and retention of otherwise degradable organic matter in soils and sediments. However, the bioavailability of organic compounds in mineral-organic-associations, especially under varying environmental conditions is not well known. To assess the impact of mineral association and warming on the decomposition of an easily respirable organic substrate (glucose), we conducted a series of laboratory incubations at different temperatures with field-collected soils from 10 to 20 cm, 50–60 cm, and 80–90 cm depth at the Blodgett Forest Research Station. We added 13C-labeled glucose either directly to native soil or sorbed to one of two synthetic iron (hydr)oxide phases (goethite and ferrihydrite) that differ in crystallinity and affinity for sorbing glucose. We incubated the soils at 25 deg C. This dataset comprises the added glucose C and the cumulative fluxes over 72 and 1896 hours. </para>      <para>We found that: (1) association with the Fe (hydr)oxide minerals reduced the decomposition rate of glucose by &gt; 99.5% relative to rate of decomposition for free glucose in soil; (2) the respiration rate per gram carbon did not differ appreciably with depth, suggesting a similar degree of decomposability for native C across depths and that under the incubation conditions total carbon availability represents the principal limitation on respiration under these conditions as opposed to reduced abundance of decomposers or moisture and oxygen limitations; (3) addition of free glucose enhanced native carbon respiration at all soil depths with the largest effect at 50–60 cm; (4) in general respiration of the organo-mineral complex (glucose and iron-(hydr)oxide) was less temperature sensitive than was respiration of native carbon; (5) the addition of organic free mineral decreased the rate of soil respiration in the intermediate 50–60 cm depth soil. The results emphasize the key role of MOAs in regulating the fluxes of carbon from soils to the atmosphere and in turn the stocks of soil carbon.</para>      <para>This dataset lists the glucose additions made to soils with and without added geothite or ferrihidrite and the C respired over the timespan of the incubations.</para>    </abstract>    <keywordSet>      <keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &gt; LAND SURFACE &gt; SOILS</keyword>      <keywordThesaurus>CATEGORICAL:GCMD</keywordThesaurus>    </keywordSet>    <keywordSet>      <keyword>mineral</keyword>      <keywordThesaurus>VARIABLE:NONE</keywordThesaurus>    </keywordSet>    <keywordSet>      <keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &gt; AGRICULTURE &gt; SOILS &gt; CARBON</keyword>      <keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &gt; LAND SURFACE &gt; SOILS &gt; SOIL RESPIRATION</keyword>      <keyword>EARTH SCIENCE &gt; LAND SURFACE &gt; SOILS &gt; ORGANIC MATTER</keyword>      <keywordThesaurus>VARIABLE:GCMD</keywordThesaurus>    </keywordSet>    <additionalInfo>      <section>        <title>Related References</title>        <para>R.C. Porras, C.E. Hicks Pries, M.S. Torn, P.S. Nico. 2018. Synthetic iron (hydr)oxide-glucose associations in subsurface soil: Effects on decomposability of mineral associated carbon. Science of The Total Environment, Volumes 613–614, Pages 342-351, ISSN 0048-9697,https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2017.08.290</para>      </section>    </additionalInfo>    <intellectualRights>      <para>This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, visit http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/.</para>    </intellectualRights>    <coverage>      <geographicCoverage>        <geographicDescription>Soils for incubation were collected at Blodgett Experimental Forest, Quintette, CA. Compartment 250.</geographicDescription>        <boundingCoordinates>          <westBoundingCoordinate>-120.660986</westBoundingCoordinate>          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-120.660986</eastBoundingCoordinate>          <northBoundingCoordinate>38.912284</northBoundingCoordinate>          <southBoundingCoordinate>38.912284</southBoundingCoordinate>        </boundingCoordinates>      </geographicCoverage>      <temporalCoverage>        <rangeOfDates>          <beginDate>            <calendarDate>2015-12-01</calendarDate>          </beginDate>          <endDate>            <calendarDate>2016-02-18</calendarDate>          </endDate>        </rangeOfDates>      </temporalCoverage>    </coverage>    <contact id="6935357528516931">      <individualName>        <givenName>Peter</givenName>        <surName>Nico</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>psnico@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-4180-9397</userId>    </contact>    <publisher id="6877400562375355">      <organizationName>Belowground Biogeochemistry Scientific Focus Area</organizationName>    </publisher>    <methods>      <methodStep>        <description>          <para>1. Fe (Hydr)oxide synthesis and characterization</para>          <para>The method of synthesis used in the present study was adapted from Schwertmann and Cornell, 2007c, Schwertmann and Cornell, 2007a. While the diversity of natural minerals is great, synthetic versions of these iron oxides are widely accepted to represent the major characteristics, e.g. crystal structure and surface area, of their natural counterparts. A detailed description of iron oxide mineral structures and their geochemical properties can be found in Cornell and Schwertmann (1996). Synthetic goethite and ferrihydrite mineral phases were prepared via titration of a 0.01 M Iron (III) nitrate solution to pH 7 with slow addition of 1 M sodium hydroxide. Once the end point was attained, the mixture was allowed to equilibrate for 1 h with base added dropwise until the solution pH stabilized. Synthetic goethite was produced by aging of the Fe hydroxide precipitate for 11 days at 80 °C which drives structural re-ordering of ferrihydrite to the well-crystalline goethite phase. Post-synthesis, Fe-(hydr)oxide phases were re-suspended in Nanopure reagent grade water (18.2 MΩ-cm), rinsed once to remove residual sodium ions, and mixed with ultrapure silica sand (Iota 6, Unimin Corp., USA). The synthetic ferrihydrite- and goethite-quartz sand slurries were mixed in a stream of air until all water was evaporated. The identity and purity of the synthetic ferrihydrite and goethite phases were confirmed via powder X-ray diffraction using a PANalytic X'Pert Pro X-ray diffractometer with Co Kα radiation source (PANalytical, Inc., the Netherlands). The BET measured surface areas for ferrihydrite and goethite of 42 and 205 m2/g, respectively were also shown to be within the expected range for each mineral type (Cornell and Schwertmann, 1996). In addition, mass of Fe per gram of goethite or ferrihydrite coated sand was determined via a 6 M HCl extraction. Samples were spiked with 1 ppm scandium internal standard and analyzed in triplicate using an iCap 6300 DUO ICP-OES (Thermo Scientific, USA).</para>        </description>      </methodStep>      <methodStep>        <description>          <para>2. Determination of adsorption maxima and preparation of 13C labeled Fe organic associations</para>          <para>Adsorption experiments with glucose and synthetic Fe (hydr)oxide coated sand were carried out at a sorbent to sorbate ratio of 1:2 over a concentration range of 1 to 50 mM in batch reactors at 25 °C for 12 h in 0.5 M NaCl background electrolyte solution in the dark. A solution pH of 6.5 was selected because it is within the range of pH (5–7) of the soils from our experimental site. Best possible effort was made to maintain sterile conditions during sample preparation through the use of autoclaved glassware, solutions, and solids. Equilibrium glucose concentrations were determined via HPLC (Agilent, USA) and the amount adsorbed by the solid Fe (hydr)oxide was computed by difference from the initial added concentration. Calculated adsorption maxima were utilized to prepare synthetic glucose Fe-(hydr)oxide associations near 100% saturation of the mineral surface. Resulting sorption data were fit to three common numeric sorption isotherms (Freundlich, Langmuir, and Linear) using a least square fitting routine in excel. In the case of the Langmuir parameters, the linearized form of the relationship was used in the fitting procedure (C/q = 1/kQmax + C/Qmax; where C is glucose concentration in mol L− 1, q is surface excess in mol g− 1; k is the Langmuir binding constant, and Qmax is the Langmuir maximum sorption capacity).</para>          <para>To prepare synthetic MOAs for the incubations, sterile 9.9 Atom % 13C-glucose solution (Cambridge Isotope Laboratories, USA) was reacted with Fe-(hydr)oxide coated sands for 12 h in the dark. Before incorporation into the soil for bioavailability tests, the synthetic MOAs were subjected to a desorption test, which constituted rinsing the MOA material in a glucose free solution and separating the wash supernatant from the solid via centrifugal filtration. The glucose concentration in solution post-rinse was subsequently determined via HPLC.</para>        </description>      </methodStep>      <methodStep>        <description>          <para>3. Soil incubations</para>          <para>Incubations were conducted using bulk soils collected from three depths (10–20, 50–60, and 80–90 cm) at the Blodgett Forest Research Station, Georgetown, CA. The soils are moderately acidic (~ pH 6.0) sandy, mixed, mesic Ultic Haploxeralfs. Soils were picked free of visible roots and transferred to 160 mL serum bottles. Sterile Nanopure (18.2 MΩ-cm) was added such that total soil water content was equivalent to 25% Volumetric Moisture Content (VMC). Experimental treatments for each depth are as follows: 13C-glucose-ferrihydrite (13C Fh) coated sand added to native soil (n = 3); 13C-glucose-goethite (13C Gt) coated sand added to native soil (n = 3); native soil with nothing added (NA) control with no glucose or mineral adduct (n = 3); ferrihydrite coated sand disturbance (Fh. Control) control added to native soil without glucose (n = 3); and 13C-labeled non-mineral associated glucose (13C glucose) control added directly to the soil (n = 3). The amount of 13C-labeled glucose added to the soil equaled 5% of the mineral-associated C as defined by density fractionation for each depth interval. All treatments were incubated at 25 °C and headspace CO2 was sampled at 0, 1, 24, and 48 h for 10-20 cm and at 0, 24, 48, and 72 h for 50–60 and 80–90 cm. Sample [CO2]ppmv was determined by gas chromatography (Shimadzu, USA). The δ13C value of the headspace CO2 was determined via syringe injection using a cavity ring down spectrometer (CRDS) isotopic CO2 analyzer with small sample injection module (SSIM; Picarro, USA). CO2 concentrations and δ13C values measured over the four time points were used to calculate flux rates and quantify the 13C-labeled glucose that was bioaccessible to soil microbes. Initial, t = 0, CO2 headspace values were subtracted from subsequent values in order to remove any impact from different concentrations of room air present in the headspace In order to compare to other results taken at 72 h, the 30 °C samples for which the longest measured time point was 48 h, were linearly extrapolated for an additional 24 h using the average CO2 flux measured from the first 48 h.</para>          <para>The total amount of carbon respired or mineralized (Clost) during the incubation was calculated using the following equation:</para>          <para>Clost = (Cf – Ci) / T</para>          <para>where the amount of carbon at the start of the incubation (Ci), either in the jar headspace or total sample was subtracted from the amount of carbon at end of the incubation (Cf), either in the headspace or solid sample, divided by the duration of the incubation. For the headspace samples, the amount of carbon removed during time course sampling was taken into account and added to the Cf value. For the cumulative carbon respired over time, the amount of carbon in the jar headspace (taking the amount of carbon removed to sample into account) for each time point was divided by the mass of the soil being incubated. The proportion of respired carbon coming from either native soil (fs) or added glucose (fg) was calculated using the following set of equations:</para>          <para>1 = fs + fg</para>          <para>13Csample = fn * 13Cn + fg * 13Cg</para>          <para>where the proportion of native soil carbon (fn) and glucose carbon (fg) were unknowns and the 13Csample was known from either the sampled headspace CO2 or the solid soil sample, the 13Cg was known (9.9 atom%), and the 13Cn was known from control samples (either headspace or soil) to which no glucose had been added. These proportions were then multiplied by the amount of carbon respired or mineralized to get the amount of native carbon or glucose carbon respired or mineralized.</para>        </description>      </methodStep>    </methods>    <project id="9cc37650-e339-4174-b9ba-a659d6fb244c" scope="system" system="ess-dive">      <title>Belowground Biogeochemistry Scientific Focus Area</title>      <personnel>        <individualName>          <givenName>Margaret</givenName>          <surName>Torn</surName>        </individualName>        <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>        <electronicMailAddress>mstorn@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>        <role>Principal Investigator</role>      </personnel>    </project>    <otherEntity id="ess-dive-7114eda6ab8e904-20221025T221511791">      <entityName>C_added__respired_Porras_Nico.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity>  </dataset></eml:eml>