<?xml version="1.0"?><eml:eml xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.1" system="ess-dive" xsi:schemaLocation="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0 https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0/eml.xsd" packageId="ess-dive-1998cb84e8a132c-20230407T225648938144">  <dataset id="dataset.id">    <alternateIdentifier>paf_771_773</alternateIdentifier>    <title>Stable isotopes of carbon dioxide (CO2), dissolved inorganic carbon (DIC), water and concentrations of greenhouse gases in a mountainous watershed (Crested Butte, Colorado)</title>    <creator id="3032046122629161">      <individualName>        <givenName>Markus</givenName>        <surName>Bill</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>mbill@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7002-2174</userId>    </creator>    <associatedParty id="3145201677142896">      <organizationName>U.S. DOE &gt; Office of Science &gt; Biological and Environmental Research (BER)</organizationName>      <userId directory="unknown">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/100006206</userId>      <role>fundingOrganization</role>    </associatedParty>    <pubDate>2022</pubDate>    <abstract>      <para>Temperature and precipitation variability in response to climate change affects water cycling of watersheds and can potentially impact water quality, water availability, elemental and molecular fluxes, and biogeochemical processes. Here we report the measurements of light stable isotopes and greenhouse gases analysis to a large multidisciplinary project addressing watershed function. Water hydrogen (H) and oxygen (O) stable isotopes of snow and water saturated soil were measured to constrain source contributions to groundwater and streamflow. In an effort to better constrain existing nitrogen and carbon cycling models in high-altitude ecosystems, carbon dioxide (CO2), nitrous oxide (N2O), methane (CH4) greenhouse gases concentrations and stable isotope signatures of CO2, dissolved inorganic carbon (DIC), and water were measured. This dataset includes one CSV file and one Excel file containing data including stable isotopes of carbon dioxide (CO2), dissolved inorganic carbon (DIC), water and concentrations of greenhouse gases. The CSV and Excel files contain the same information/data but have included both versions for accessibility.</para>    </abstract>    <keywordSet>      <keyword>nitrogen cycle</keyword>      <keyword> carbon cycle</keyword>      <keyword> water cycle</keyword>      <keywordThesaurus>CATEGORICAL:NONE</keywordThesaurus>    </keywordSet>    <keywordSet>      <keyword>Isotopes</keyword>      <keyword>Soil/Dissolved Gas Concentrations</keyword>      <keywordThesaurus>VARIABLE:NONE</keywordThesaurus>    </keywordSet>    <additionalInfo>      <section>        <title>Related References</title>        <para>Additional metadata on specific locations within the watershed are provided in the following related data package:</para>        <para>Varadharajan C ; Kakalia Z ; Banfield J ; Berkelhammer M ; Brodie E ; Christianson D ; Dafflon B ; Carbone M S ; Carroll R ; Chadwick K D ; Christensen J ; Enquist B J ; Fox P ; Henderson M ; Gochis D ; Kueppers L ; Powell T ; Matheus Carnevali P ; Singha K ; Sorensen P ; Tokunaga T ; Versteeg R ; Wilkins M ; Williams K ; Worsham M ; Wu Y ; Agarwal D (2020): Location Identifiers, Metadata, and Map for Field Measurements at the East River Watershed, Colorado, USA. Watershed Function SFA. doi:10.15485/1660962</para>      </section>    </additionalInfo>    <intellectualRights>      <para>This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, visit http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/.</para>    </intellectualRights>    <coverage>      <geographicCoverage>        <geographicDescription>The East River (ER) is a snow‐dominated, headwater basin of the Upper Colorado River Basin (UCRB) located in the western United States. The ER is the designated testbed of Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory's Watershed Function Scientific Focus Area (WFSFA). Through WFSFA, observational networks have been established to measure stream discharge and precipitation chemistry. The ER is considered representative of many snow‐dominated headwaters of the Rocky Mountains. The study domain encompasses nearly 85 square km, a 1.4‐km vertical drop in elevation (4,120 to 2,760 m) and pristine alpine, subalpine, montane, and riparian ecosystems. The ER contains high‐energy mountain streams to low‐energy meandering floodplains and is eroding primarily into the Cretaceous, carbon‐rich, marine shale of the Mancos Formation. Additional metadata on specific locations within the watershed are provided in the following related data package: Varadharajan C. et al. (2020) doi:10.15485/1660962</geographicDescription>        <boundingCoordinates>          <westBoundingCoordinate>-107.05</westBoundingCoordinate>          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-106.88</eastBoundingCoordinate>          <northBoundingCoordinate>39.034</northBoundingCoordinate>          <southBoundingCoordinate>38.88</southBoundingCoordinate>        </boundingCoordinates>      </geographicCoverage>      <temporalCoverage>        <rangeOfDates>          <beginDate>            <calendarDate>2017-05-01</calendarDate>          </beginDate>          <endDate>            <calendarDate>2019-09-01</calendarDate>          </endDate>        </rangeOfDates>      </temporalCoverage>    </coverage>    <contact id="7653579655032751">      <individualName>        <givenName>Markus</givenName>        <surName>Bill</surName>      </individualName>      <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName>      <electronicMailAddress>mbill@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>      <userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7002-2174</userId>    </contact>    <publisher id="4267438979065510">      <organizationName>Watershed Function SFA</organizationName>    </publisher>    <methods>      <methodStep>        <description>          <para>Hydrogen and oxygen isotope ratios of water were measured using an Off-Axis Integrated Cavity Output Spectrometer (Off-Axis ICOS) coupled to an autosampler interfaced with a heated injector block. CO2, CH4 and N2O concentrations were quantified on a GC- 2014 Shimadzu gas chromatograph. Carbon and oxygen isotope ratio of CO2 from gas samples were measured in aliquots injected into helium-flushed exetainer vials. Then, the CO2 was analyzed using a headspace autosampler connected to a Tracegas preconcentrator interfaced to Micromass JA Series Isoprime isotope ratio mass spectrometer. Carbon isotope ratio of dissolved inorganic carbon (DIC) from water samples was determined in aliquots injected into helium-flushed exetainer vials containing phosphoric acid (H3PO4). The CO2 generated from the reaction of DIC with H3PO4 was analyzed using a headspace autosampler connected to a Tracegas preconcentrator interfaced to Micromass JA Series Isoprime isotope ratio mass spectrometer.</para>        </description>      </methodStep>    </methods>    <project id="024b867d-25e3-4025-b68c-6598aded7aa2" scope="system" system="ess-dive">      <title>Watershed Function SFA</title>      <personnel>        <individualName>          <givenName>Eoin</givenName>          <surName>Brodie</surName>        </individualName>        <organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Lab</organizationName>        <electronicMailAddress>elbrodie@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress>        <role>Principal Investigator</role>      </personnel>    </project>    <otherEntity id="ess-dive-edb16f31096aaeb-20220331T150132275625">      <entityName>ERiver 170508-190321 dD d13C d18O greenhouse campaigns exp.xlsx</entityName>      <entityType>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</entityType>    </otherEntity>    <otherEntity id="ess-dive-95b754df1a5567c-20220331T150131822933">      <entityName>ERiver 170508-190321 dD d13C d18O greenhouse campaigns exp.csv</entityName>      <entityType>text/csv</entityType>    </otherEntity>  </dataset></eml:eml>