<eml:eml xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.1" xsi:schemaLocation="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0 https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0/eml.xsd" packageId="ess-dive-0293d1f436345d2-20230918T163827734" system="ess-dive"><dataset><title>2016 Floodplain Geochemistry from the East River Watershed, Colorado</title><creator id="4625015060886904"><individualName><givenName>Patricia</givenName><surName>Fox</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>pmfox@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress><userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-5264-1876</userId></creator><creator id="3214704985177138"><individualName><givenName>Dipankar</givenName><surName>Dwivedi</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>ddwivedi@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress><userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0003-1788-1900</userId></creator><creator id="3414597634086352"><individualName><givenName>Bhavna</givenName><surName>Arora</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>barora@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress><userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7841-886X</userId></creator><creator id="4119767573819023"><individualName><givenName>Peter</givenName><surName>Nico</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>psnico@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress><userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-4180-9397</userId></creator><associatedParty id="4064115124337764"><organizationName>U.S. DOE &#x3E; Office of Science &#x3E; Biological and Environmental Research (BER)</organizationName><userId directory="unknown">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/100006206</userId><role>fundingOrganization</role></associatedParty><pubDate>2023</pubDate><abstract><para>This dataset includes groundwater geochemistry data from floodplain piezometers collected as a part of the Watershed Function Scientific Focus Area (SFA) located in the Upper Colorado River Basin. The data were collected in order to investigate the role of hyporheic exchange and other river corridor processes on riverine export of solutes. Floodplain piezometers installed in several meanders (Meander C, Meander D, and Meander O) in the vicinity of the Pumphouse were sampled at several dates in 2016. Data includes in-field measurements (pH, electrical conductivity, oxidation reduction potential, dissolved oxygen, dissolved Fe(II), dissolved sulfide, and groundwater level) along with laboratory measurements (dissolved inorganic carbon, dissolved organic carbon, metals and major cations). Five files are included in this dataset, including: sample locations and depths in a csv file (metadata.csv), aqueous geochemistry data in a csv file, analytical detection limits in a csv file, a file-level metadata (flmd.csv) file, and a data dictionary (dd.csv) file. Data that was below the detection limit is reported as one half of the detection limit and missing data is listed as "-9999".</para></abstract><keywordSet><keyword>groundwater</keyword><keyword>cations</keyword><keyword>metals</keyword><keyword>pumphouse</keyword><keyword>ESS-DIVE File Level Metadata Reporting Format</keyword><keywordThesaurus>CATEGORICAL:NONE</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet><keywordSet><keyword>Groundwater Level</keyword><keyword>Cations</keyword><keyword>Patriculate/Dissolved Inorganic Carbon</keyword><keyword>Patriculate/Dissolved Organic Carbon</keyword><keyword>Dissolved Oxygen (DO)</keyword><keywordThesaurus>VARIABLE:NONE</keywordThesaurus></keywordSet><additionalInfo><section><title>Related References</title><para>Additional metadata on specific locations within the watershed are provided in the following related data package:</para><para>Varadharajan C ; Kakalia Z ; Burrus M ; O'Ryan D ; Alper E ; Banfield J ; Berkelhammer M ; Beutler C ; Brodie E ; Brown W ; Carbone M S ; Carroll R ; Christianson D ; Chou C ; Crystal-Ornelas R ; Chadwick K D ; Christensen J ; Dafflon B ; Elbashandy H ; Enquist B J ; Fox P ; Gochis D ; Henderson M ; Johnson D ; Kueppers L ; Matheus Carnevali P ; Newman A ; Powell T ; Singha K ; Sorensen P ; Sprenger M ; Tokunaga T ; Versteeg R ; Wilkins M ; Williams K ; Worsham M ; Wong C ; Wu Y ; Agarwal D (2022): Location Identifiers, Metadata, and Map for Field Measurements at the East River Watershed, Colorado, USA (Version 3.0). Watershed Function SFA, ESS-DIVE repository. Dataset. doi:10.15485/1660962</para></section></additionalInfo><intellectualRights><para>This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, visit http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/.</para></intellectualRights><coverage><geographicCoverage><geographicDescription>The East River (ER) is a snow‐dominated, headwater basin of the Upper Colorado River Basin (UCRB) located in the western United States. The ER is the designated testbed of Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory's Watershed Function Scientific Focus Area (WFSFA). Through WFSFA, observational networks have been established to measure stream discharge and precipitation chemistry. The ER is considered representative of many snow‐dominated headwaters of the Rocky Mountains. The study domain encompasses nearly 85 square km, a 1.4‐km vertical drop in elevation (4,120 to 2,760 m) and pristine alpine, subalpine, montane, and riparian ecosystems. The ER contains high‐energy mountain streams to low‐energy meandering floodplains and is eroding primarily into the Cretaceous, carbon‐rich, marine shale of the Mancos Formation. Additional metadata on specific locations within the watershed are provided in the following related data package: Varadharajan C. et al. (2022) doi:10.15485/1660962</geographicDescription><boundingCoordinates><westBoundingCoordinate>-107.05</westBoundingCoordinate><eastBoundingCoordinate>-106.88</eastBoundingCoordinate><northBoundingCoordinate>39.034</northBoundingCoordinate><southBoundingCoordinate>38.88</southBoundingCoordinate></boundingCoordinates></geographicCoverage><temporalCoverage><rangeOfDates><beginDate><calendarDate>2016-07-18</calendarDate></beginDate><endDate><calendarDate>2016-11-01</calendarDate></endDate></rangeOfDates></temporalCoverage></coverage><contact id="2446448965118131"><individualName><givenName>Patricia</givenName><surName>Fox</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>pmfox@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress><userId directory="https://orcid.org">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-5264-1876</userId></contact><publisher id="2491523142617320"><organizationName>Watershed Function SFA</organizationName></publisher><methods><methodStep><description><para>Manual water level measurements were performed using an electrical water level meter.</para><para>Groundwater samples were collected using a peristaltic pump from piezometers after purging standing water. A multi-parameter probe was used to measure pH, electrical conductivity and oxidation-reduction potential (ORP) immediately after sampling in the field. Dissolved oxygen (DO), Fe(II), and S(-II) (sulfide) were measured colorimetrically in the field using a portable spectrophotometer (CHEMetrics, Inc.). Filtered samples (0.45 um PVDF syringe filter) were collected for dissolved inorganic carbon (DIC) and organic carbon (DOC) in amber glass vials and cations (various elements) in polyethylene vials and shipped to the lab for analysis.</para><para>DO was measured on unfiltered groundwater using either with the indigo carmine method (Chemetrics #K-7513, 1–15 ppm) or the Rhodazine D™ method (Chemetrics #K-7553, 0–1 ppm). \n\nFe(II) was measured on filtered groundwater using the phenanthroline method (Chemetrics #K-6203, 0-6 ppm).</para><para>S(-II) was measured on filtered groundwater using the methylene blue method (Chemetrics #K-9503, 0-3 ppm).</para><para>DIC and DOC samples were refrigerated at 4 degrees C for storage and shipment. Groundwater samples were analyzed for total dissolved carbon and dissolved organic carbon (DOC) on a Shimadzu TOC-V analyzer with a nondispersive infrared detector, and dissolved inorganic carbon was determined by the difference. Total dissolved carbon was measured by catalytically aided combustion at 680 °C, and DOC samples were analyzed by nonpurgeable organic carbon, for which samples were acidified with HCl and purged with nitrogen gas in order to remove inorganic carbon prior to the analysis. \n\nElemental concentrations were measured in "cation" samples by inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP-MS, Perkin-Elmer Elan DRC II) after acidification and dilution with ultrapure 0.16 M nitric acid and internal standard addition.\n\nDetection limits are listed in the file titled "units and detection limits.csv" and were either reported by instrument manufacturer [DO, Fe(II), and S(-II)] or calculated as 5 times the standard deviation of a MilliQ water blank (all others). Any data below the detection limit is reported as one half of the detection limit. Missing data is reported as "-9999".</para><para>"-9999" indicates that the parameter was not measured.</para></description></methodStep></methods><project id="024b867d-25e3-4025-b68c-6598aded7aa2" scope="system" system="ess-dive"><title>Watershed Function SFA</title><personnel id="9935214000758924"><individualName><givenName>Eoin</givenName><surName>Brodie</surName></individualName><organizationName>Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>elbrodie@lbl.gov</electronicMailAddress><role>principalInvestigator</role></personnel></project><otherEntity id="ess-dive-397cbc0b20ed378-20230918T163817838"><entityName>water_sampling_2016_archive_v1.csv</entityName><entityType>text/csv</entityType></otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-1291321f9215839-20230918T163817826"><entityName>units_and_detection_limits.csv</entityName><entityType>text/csv</entityType></otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-38e4079f82218aa-20230918T163817817"><entityName>metadata.csv</entityName><entityType>text/csv</entityType></otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-3632ec31df889eb-20230918T163817802"><entityName>flmd.csv</entityName><entityType>text/csv</entityType></otherEntity><otherEntity id="ess-dive-1fbf66b668332f2-20230918T163817763"><entityName>dd.csv</entityName><entityType>text/csv</entityType></otherEntity></dataset></eml:eml>